我相信Harvey Dent.
I believed in Harvey Dent.
-Pavel博士 我是CIA -他不是一個人
- Dr. Pavel, I'm CIA. - He wasn't alone.
-你不能帶朋友陪同 -他們不是我朋友
- You don't get to bring friends. - There are not my friends.
-別擔心 不收你錢 -我為什麼要帶上他們
- Don't worry no charge for them. - And why would I want them?
他們能抬高你的身價
They were trying to up your price.
他們是給那個僱傭兵賣命的 那個面具人
They work for the mercenary, a masked man.
Bane
Bane?
帶他們登機 我會向上級匯報的
Get them on board. I'll call them in.
我剛向局裡提交了引渡計劃
The flight plan I just filed the agency,
名單只有我 我手下 Pavel博士
list me, my man, Dr Pavel here
和你們其中一個
but only one of you.
第一個開口說話的可以留在飛機上
The first one to talk get to stay on my aircraft.
誰指使你去綁架Pavel博士的
Who paid you to grab Dr. Pavel?
他飛得不夠漂亮啊 下一個誰來
He didn't fly so good, who wants to try next?
跟我說說Bane 為什麼他要帶面具
Tell me about Bane! Why does he wear a mask?
作為跑腿小弟你也太忠心耿耿了吧
A lot of loyalty for a hired gun!
也許他好奇為什麼有人把他扔下飛機前
Or perhaps he was wondering why someone would shoot a man
還想射死他
before throwing him out of the plane.
終於有人開口了 你是誰
At least you can talk. Who are you?
我們是誰不重要
It doesn't matter who we are.
我們的計劃才重要
What matters is our plan.
我戴面具之前 從沒有人關心我是誰
No one cared who I was until I put on the mask.
-我摘掉你的面具 你會死麼
- If I pulled that off, will you die?
-會疼死人的
- It will be extremely painful ...
-你還會怕痛?  -我是怕你痛啊
- You're a big guy. - ... For you.
被捕也是你的計劃麼
Was getting caught part of your plan?
當然了
Of course.
Pavel博士拒絕了我們的條件 卻接受了你的
Dr Pavel refused that offer in favour of yours.
我們必須要知道他都跟你說了些什麼
We had to find out what he told you.
沒有 我什麼都沒說
Nothing! I said nothing!
那恭喜啊 你被捕了
Congratulations! You got yourself caught!
長官
Sir ...
你驚天計劃的下一步是什麼呢
Now what's the next step of your master plan?
飛機墜毀
Crashing this plane ...
無人生還
...with no survivors.
求救 求救
Mayday! Mayday!
不
No!
他們希望我們中有一個人能遇難 兄弟
They expect one of us in the wreck, brother.
-火點燃了嗎  -是的 烈火已經開始燃燒
- Did we started the fire? - Yes. The fire rises.
冷靜點 博士 這還不是害怕的時候呢
Calm down, doctor. Now this is not the time for fear.
現在才是
That comes later.
Harvey Dent日也許不是我們最古老的節日
Harvey Dent's day may not be our oldest holiday
我們今日相聚 卻是因為他是最重要的
but we're here tonight because it's one the most important.
Harvey Dent對於犯罪分子毫不妥協的立場
Harvey Dent's uncompromising stand against organized crime.
使哥譚市的治安
It made Gotham a safer
從他去世那一年開始好轉
place than it was at the time of his death,
8年前
eight years ago.
這座城見證了歷史性的轉折
This city has seen a historical turn around
天下無城不惡 但這裡卻靜若天堂
No city is without crime but this city is
靜若天堂 正是因為
without organized crime because of
Dent的行為 才使得
the Dent's act gave law
法律有了粉碎犯罪集團的利齒
enforcement teeth in it's fight against the Mafia.
近日 有人開始發表意見說要廢除Dent法案
Now people are talking about repealing the Dent's act
我也要發表意見 只要我在就別想
and to them I'll say not on my watch.
要感謝Wayne基金主持這次盛會
I want to thank Wayne Foundation for hosting this event.
我聽聞今晚Wayne先生不能前來
Now I'm told that Mr. Wayne couldn't be here tonight,
但我相信 精神上他與我們同在
but I'm sure that he's with us in spirit.
現在 我要發表重要講話
and now, I'm going to give away to an important voice ...
最近有人見過Wayne麼
Who can lay eyes on Wayne these days?
沒 好幾年都沒見過了
No one has, not in years.
人們對這個面具和斗篷下的殺人狂徒抱有信仰
People put in faith in a murderous thug in a mask and a cape.
一個最終露出真面目的狂徒
A thug who shows his true nature when
一個最終背叛偉大的Dent
he betrayed the trust of
並極度殘忍將其殺害的狂徒
this great man and murdered him in cold blood.
可人兒 幹嘛急著送飯
Sweetheart, what's so fast with the chow?
蝦球
Shrimp balls?
-Jim Gordon 能告訴你Harvey Dent的真相 -謝謝
-Jim Gordon can tell you the truth about Harvey Dent -Thank you
還是由他自己講述吧 有請Gordon警長
Let him tell you himself. Commissioner Gordon!
真相就是
The truth ...
我準備了Harvey Dent事件真相的發言稿
I have... A speech telling the truth about Harvey Dent.
只是 或許時機未到
Maybe the time isn't right.
或許 現在
Maybe right now...
你們只需要知道
All you need to know is that ...
黑門監獄收押的千名罪犯
there are one thousand inmates in Blackgate Prison
都是Dent法案的結果
as a direct result of the Dent's act.
那些暴力罪犯
These are violent criminals
犯罪集團的主力打手
essential thugs in the organized crime machine.
也許 我應該說
Maybe, for now I should say
Harvey Dent並沒有
about the death of Harvey Dent's is this...
白白犧牲
It has not been for nothing.
你見過這房子的主人麼
Did you see the guy who owns the house?
沒 我聽說他從來沒出過東樓
No. I heard he never leaves the east wing.
你知道麼 我聽說他出了車禍
You know, I heard he had an accident.
是哦 怪不得會毀容
Yeah that he's disfigured ...
Till先生 為什麼你的人會佔用主樓梯
Mr. Till! Why are your people using the main staircase?
-還有 Bolton小姐在哪裡 -她在吧檯 先生 我能效勞麼
- And where is Mrs. Bolton? - She's at the bar, sir. Can I help?
去東樓
Get to the east wing.
打開門 把托盤放在桌子上
Unlock door, put the tray on the table,
再把門鎖上
and lock the door again.
就這些
Nothing more.
真是抱歉 Tate小姐 我通報了可是先生不願意見您
I'm sorry, Miss Tate. I tried but he won't see you.
你呀 別難過 他不是針對你一個
You know, you mustn't take it personally.
大家都知道Wayne獨自躲在裡面
Everyone knows that Wayne is hold up in there with
用幾年沒剪過的8寸長指甲給孩子疊衣服呢
8 inch nails paving into mason's jar
讓我等這麼久 你真是太好了
It's very good of you to let me on the ground.
你幹嘛要浪費時間在
Why are you wasting your time trying to talk
一個把你的投資花在
to a man who throw away your investment
拯救世界的面子工程上的人
on some save the world vanity project?
他不能給你賺錢 我能
He can't get your money back, I can.
我可以花時間給你解釋拯救世界的企劃案
I could try explaining that the save the world project,
賺不賺錢 都是值得投資的 Daggett先生
vain or not, is worth investing in, Mr. Daggett.
但你只懂得錢和權的附屬品
But you understand only money and the power you think it buys.
那我幹嘛要浪費時間呢 真是的
So why waste my time, indeed?
二次報告移交完畢
Second report shift report's in,
你應該跟市長多打交道
You should spend some time with the mayor.
那是你的事
Well that's your department.
有人給他看過犯罪統計麼
Did anyone shows him the crime stats?
他一向相信直覺的
He goes by his guts,
不管犯罪率是多少他都放不下心來
and it continue to bothers him no matter what the numbers.
他老婆肯定愛死他了
Must be popular with his wife.
才不是呢 他老婆帶著孩子回克利夫蘭娘家去了
Not really. she took the kids and left for Cleveland.
我們有的是時間干他的活
We have plenty of time for visits.
市長春天就會炒了他
The Mayor going to dump him in the spring.
真的麼 他可是個英雄啊
Really? But he's a hero.
天下太平 誰還需要英雄
War hero. This is peace time.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry sorry.
我真的很抱歉 Wayne先生
I'm so terribly sorry, Mr. Wayne!
是Wayne先生 對麼
It is Mr. Wayne, isn't it?
雖然先生你沒有8寸長甲 也沒有明顯的疤痕
Although you don't have long nails or facial scars sir...
外面都是這麼說我的麼
That's what they say about me?
都是因為 沒人見得到你
Because you know, no one ever sees you.
你項鏈很漂亮嘛
That's a beautiful necklace!
讓我想起我媽媽的那一條
Reminds me of one that belongs to my mother.
不會是同一條吧
It can't be the same one,
她的那條鎖在保險箱裡呢
because her Pearls are in the safe.
製造商說這可是無法破解的
The manufacturer clearly explained that it is uncrackable.
哎呀 沒人跟我說過他無法破解呀
Oops Nobody told me it was uncrackable.
抱歉我恐怕不能讓你帶走它
I'm afraid I can't let you take those.
你不會打女人的
Look you wouldn't beat up a woman,
而且 我也不打瘸子
anymore than I would beat up a cripple.
當然 偶爾也是會有例外的
Of course, sometimes exceptions have to be made.
晚安 Wayne先生
Good night, Mr. Wayne!
-能搭個便車麼 -正合我意
- Can I have a ride? - You read my mind!
走吧
Let's go!
Tate小姐又來請求見面了
Ms. Tate was asking to see you again.
-她可真固執啊 -還很漂亮呢
- She's very persistent. - And quite lovely.
-萬一你有興趣呢 -沒興趣
- In case you were wondering. - I wasn't.
-你在幹嘛 -採集指紋
- What are you doing? - Examining print dust.
我們被搶了
We've been robbed.
誰讓你撤除警報系統的
And this your idea of unsounding the alarm, is it?
她把項鏈偷了 追蹤裝置什麼的也都拿走了
She took pearls, tracking device and all.
-她? -一個女傭
- She? - One of the maids.
也許你該禁止她們來東樓
Perhaps you should stop letting them in this part of the house.
也許你該學學自己鋪床
Perhaps you should start learning to make your own bed.
-為什麼要採集指紋呢 -不是我 是她在採集
- Why were you dusting for prints? - I wasn't. She does.
長官 Gilly議員的夫人一直打來說
Sir! Congressman Gilly's wife been calling
議員從Wayne基金的活動結束後
in apparently the congressman never made
就沒回過家
it home after the Wayne Foundation event.
現在的警察就只能幹這個了
That's the job for the police.
你跟Dent早就把烏煙瘴氣都掃乾淨了
When you and Dent clean up the streets, you've cleaned them good.
再過幾天我們該去追查圖書館過期借據了
Pretty soon we will be chasing down an over due library books.
但是 你仍然是一副身陷戰場的摸樣
and yet, here you're act like we're still at war.
-你叫什麼 孩子 -Blake 長官
- What's your name, son? - Blake, sir.
你有話想問我麼 Blake警員
You have something you want to ask me officer Blake?
是關於那一夜 8年前的今夜
It's about that night, this night,
Dent去世的那一夜
eight years ago, the night Dent died.
最後關於蝙蝠俠的聲明說
The last confirm sighting of The Batman.
他殺害了那麼多人 放倒了2梯隊特警
Who murders those people, takes down two SWAT teams,
擰斷了Dent的脖子 然後就 消失了
brakes Dent's neck and then just vanishes.
我不懂你想問什麼
I'm not hearing the question.
難道你不想知道他是誰麼
Don't you want to know who he was?
我非常清楚他是誰
I know exactly who he was.
他是蝙蝠俠
He was The Batman.
我們去看看議員夫人吧
Let's go see about The Congressman's wife.
Wayne少爺
Master Wayne!
你已經很久沒下來過了
You haven't been down here in a long time.
我來找關於珠寶小賊的線索
I'm trying to finding more about our jewel thief.
我比對了她的指紋
I ran her prints.
除非她減肥過度了
Unless she loss a lot of weight,
她用的是別人的指紋
she was wearing someone else's fingerprints.
她不錯喲
She's good.
她是不錯 但項鏈上 不是有追蹤器麼
She may be, but we a..Trace on the necklace.
有是有  我把去過的地方和警方
We do, so I cross reference the address she went back to,
高端盜竊組的資料做了交叉比對
with police data on high end thieves and these
找到了Selina Kyle
and Selina Kyle.
她犯過不少事兒
Her database's are full
但罪名從沒成立過
of close calls and tips around the fences.
她是不錯 但不巧她遇到我了
She's good, but the ground is shrinking beneath her feet.
我們得在她把項鏈脫手之前報警啊
We should send the police before she fences her purposes.
她不會脫手的 她太喜歡那條項鏈了
She won't. She likes it too much
而且項鏈並不是她的目的
and they weren't what she was after.
-她的目的是 -我的指紋
- What was she after? - My fingerprints.
她把打印碳粉混合了石墨塗在保險櫃上
It was printer toner mixed with graphite on the safe.
能得到完整指紋 而且無法追蹤
It gives you good pull and and it's untraceable.
精彩 你們倆真該一起喝杯咖啡交換電話
Fascinating! You two should exchanging notes over coffee.
你想撮合我跟一個小偷
So you're trying to set me up with a jewel thief?
要是有人能帶你回正常世界的話
At this point, I'd set you up with a chimpanzee,
就算是母猩猩我都願意撮合
if it'd bring you back to the world.
- 外面的世界已經不再屬於我了 -這正是問題所在
- There's nothing out there for me. - And that's the problem.
你把戰服和面具高高掛起 但你卻無法繼續
You hung up your cape and your mask but you didn't move on.
你從未真正地生活過  你早晚有一天會
You never went to find a life, you'll find some how...
Alfred
Alfred ...
我曾經擁有過
I did find someone.
我知道 然後你又失去了一切 但生活就是如此 少爺
I know, and you lost them but that's all part of living sir.
但你並不是在生活 你只是在等待
But you're not living, you're just waiting,
等著災難降臨
hoping things to go bad again.
記得你離開哥譚市那一次麼
Remember when you left Gotham?
那時還沒有這一切 還沒有蝙蝠俠
Before all this, before Batman,
你一走就是7年
You've been gone for seven years.
7年來我一直等你 希望你不再回來
Seven years I've waited hoping that you wouldn't come back.
每一年 我都給自己放假
Every year, I took a holiday.
去佛羅倫薩 阿爾諾河畔喝咖啡
I went to Florence's cafe on the banks of the Arno.
每一個良宵 我都坐下點一杯苦酒
Every fine evening, I'll sit there and ordered a Fernet Branca.
幻想著
I had this fantasy..
我朝對面的桌子看過去
that I would look across the tables ...
在人群中看見了你
and I'll see you there ...
帶著妻子 或許還帶著孩子
... With a wife maybe a couple of kids.
你我彼此不用言語
You won't say anything to me, nor me to you.
但我們都明白 你過得很好
But we both know that you made it, that you were happy.
我從沒希望你重新回到哥譚
I never wanted you to come back to Gotham.
我一直都清楚 這裡除了苦痛悲哀
I always know that there was nothing
再沒有什麼可以給你
else here for you except pain and tragedy
我希望你擁有得更多
and I wanted something more for you than that.
一直都希望
I still do.
一個月大概出水兩次
It washed up here a couples of times a month
天越冷量越多
even more when it gets colder.
寄居在下水道的流浪者
Homeless sheltering in the tunnels.
我們把他從水裡撈出來
We pulled him from the
就沒碰他了
base but other than that, we didn't touch it.
什麼
What?
他叫Jimmy 是St. Swithin收容所的
His name is Jimmy. He's from St. Swithin's.
他是我學校的孩子 我給他們隊當教練
He's the boy on my school. I coached the ball.
Jimmy幾個月前搬出去了
Jimmy has not been around for months.
-為什麼 -Blake 你知道為什麼
- No, why? - Blake, you know why.
他超齡了
He aged out.
我們沒有資金去供給16歲以上的孩子
We don't have the resources to keep the boys on after 16.
Wayne基金不是一直資助嗎
I thought the Wayne Foundation gave money for them.
近幾年沒有了
Not for the past couple of years.
-他弟弟也在這兒吧 -Mark 我會告訴他的
- He has a brother here, doesn't he? - Mark. I'll tell him.
我來說吧 你不介意的話
I'd like to. If that's alright.
你知道他在下水道裡幹什麼嗎
You know what he was doing down there in the tunnels?
很多超齡的孩子都去下水道了
A lot of guys go in down in the tunnels when they aged out.
他們說可以住在裡面 還有工作
They said he lived down there. They says there's work down there.
工作
Work?
下水道裡能有什麼工作
What kind of work you can find in the sewers?
肯定比地上的好唄
More than you can find out here I guess.
- 你也知道蝙蝠俠 -當然了
- So you know about him. - Of course.
你覺得蝙蝠俠還會回來麼
Do you think he's coming back?
不知道
I don't know...
你還帶了個男的
You brought a date?
我喜歡有人跟著 還能幫我開個門什麼的
I like someone around to open doors for me.
右手 拿到了局部的指紋
Right hand, I got partials.
很好
Very nice!
別急嘛 帥哥 我要的東西呢
Not so fast, handsome! You've got something for me?
哦 對了
Oh yes.
我不知道你想拿Wayne先生的指紋幹嘛
I don't know what you're planning to do with Mr. Wayne's prints,
但我猜 你很需要拇指吧
but I'm guessing, you need his thumb.
-不太會數數麼 -我會數數
- You don't count so good huh? - I count fine.
實際上 我現在就開始 數到10
In fact, I'm counting to 10 right now.
好吧
Okay ...
我朋友就在外面 按發送就好
My friend's outside, just...hit send.
-這地方真暗
- This place is a little dim.
-等會兒就亮了 不騙你
- I'll light up in a minute. Trust me.
沒事吧
Is everything okay?
沒事 等會兒見
Great. Catch you later.
要是大家都按規矩辦事兒 不就簡單了麼
It would've been a lot easier to just give me what we agreed.
我們不能留活口
We can't have loose ends.
不管你多漂亮 都沒用
and even in that dress, no one going to miss you.
不 我那位朋友
No but my friend over there,
城裡的每個警察都在找他
Every cop in the city is missing him.
聰明 不過他們
That's cute! But they're
不會來這種地方找的
not going to be looking in a place like this.
這我就不敢肯定了 你剛才還用了他的電話呢
I don't know, you did use your cell phone.
警察 快趴下
Police! Get down now!
救命啊
Help me!
用力壓著傷口 親愛的
Keep some pressure on that, sweetheart.
記得打給我啊
Call me?
-小心點 小姐 -他在流血 快去救他
- Careful, Miss. - He's bleeding! You gotta help him!
我找到議員了
I've got The Congressman.
那邊
There!
下水道 掀開 快派人下去
The manhole! Get this out. Get the GWPD down here!
你們三個 跟我下去
You three, down with me!
你們倆 你下去 堵住下個出口
You two, you go down, cover the next exit!
什麼情況 他下去了?
What? He went down there?
- 我們要下去是吧 -那只是煤氣爆炸 孩子
- We're going down there, right? - That was a gas explosion, kid.
什麼煤氣 這是下水道
What gas? It's a sewer.
沒弄清楚下面有什麼之前 誰都不准下去
No one goes in there until we know what's down there.
我知道下面有什麼 長官 我們的警長
We know who's there sir, a police commissioner.
能有人把這個愣頭青拖走嗎
Someone get this hot head out of here.
工程單位的人怎麼還沒來
and where's that GWP guy?
你在這幹嘛
Why are you here?
回答他
Answer him!
我是問你
I was asking you.
這是本市警長
It's a Police Commissioner.
-那你還帶他下來 -我們不知道該怎麼處理
- And you brought him down here? - We didn't know what to do.
-我們想 -你害怕了
- We just thought ... - You panicked.
你的軟弱導致了其他三個人的死亡
And your weakness cost the lives of three others.
不 他只是有點
No. He's a little ...
搜他身 搜完我再殺你
Search him. Then I'll kill you.
他死了
He's dead!
死要見屍
So show me his body!
這裡的水循環很複雜
The water runs to any one of the out flows.
我們不可能找到他的
We'll never find him.
-那就跟著他 -跟著他?
- Follow him. - Follow him?
警長 警長 嘿
Detective! Detective! Hey!
快醒醒
You awake?
我要見Bruce Wayne
I need to see Bruce Wayne.
不好意思 Wayne先生只接受預約來訪
I'm sorry, Mr. Wayne doesn't take unscheduled calls,
警察也不見
even from a police officer.
如果我去申請搜查令
If I go get a warrant for
來調查Harvey Dent的謀殺案呢
the investigation of Harvey Dent's murder,
還不能算預約麼
it still counts as an unscheduled?
警官 我有什麼可以效勞的
How can I do for you officer?
Gordon警長中槍了
Commissioner Gordon been shot.
他追蹤一個槍手進了下水道
He chased a gun man down in the sewers.
我把他拉出來後 他一直說著什麼下水道裡的軍隊
When I pulled him out, he was babbling about an underground army,
有個戴面具的貝恩
a masked man called Bane.
你不應該
Shouldn't you be telling
跟你上級匯報這個麼
this to your superiors officers about this?
上級問他看沒看見短嘴鱷
They asked if he saw any giant alligators.
他需要你
He needs you.
他需要蝙蝠俠
He needs The Batman.
Gordon警長知道
Commissioner Gordon thinks ...
哦 他不知道 他才不管你是誰
Oh he doesn't know. He didn't care who you are.
但我們以前見過
But we met before.
很久很久以前我還是個孩子 在St. Swithin
There was a long ago, I was a kid at St. Swithin's ...
曾經被Wayne基金贊助的收容所
Used to funded by The Wayne Foundation.
是個孤兒院
It's an orphanage.
我小時候媽媽車禍去世了
My mother died when I was small in a car accident.
但我不記得
But I don't remember it.
幾年後爸爸被槍殺
My dad got shot a couple of years later
以為一身賭債
for a gambling debt.
那個我倒是記得
Oh I remember that one just fine.
並不是每個人都懂
Not a lot of people knows
那種深入骨髓的憤怒
what it feels like to be angry in your bones.
他們總是理解 那些養父母
I mean they understand. The fosters parents.
他們都說理解
Everybody understands ...
一段時間後
... For a while.
他們開始讓憤怒的孩子
Then they want the angry
做那些他們做不到的事
little kid to do something he knows he can't do
放下
move on.
不久之後 他們就不再理解了
After a while they stop understanding.
他們把憤怒的孩子送到孤兒院
They send the angry little kid to a boy's school.
我領悟的太晚了
I figured it out too late.
你得學著掩蓋憤怒
You got to learn to hide the anger,
對著鏡子 練習微笑
practice smiling in the mirror.
就像戴著面具一樣
It's like putting on a mask.
有一天你出現了 開著香車
So you show up this one day, in a cool car,
摟著美女
pretty girl in your arms.
我們都好激動 Bruce Wayne 那個億萬富翁孤兒
we were so excited! Bruce Wayne, billionaire orphan?
我們經常編些關與你的故事 你的傳奇
We used to make up stories about you man, legends ...
對於其他的小孩
and you know the other kids,
就只是故事而已
that's all it was, it's just stories.
但當我見到你 我知道你是誰
But when I saw you, I knew who you really were.
我見過你臉上的表情
I seen that look on your face before.
就是我逼自己練習的那個
It's the same one that I taught myself.
我不懂你為什麼要給Dent背黑鍋
I don't why you take the fault of Dent's murder
但我依舊是蝙蝠俠的信徒
but I still a believer in The Batman.
就算你不是蝙蝠俠
Even if you're not...
為什麼你說你們孤兒院
Why did you say that your boy's home
曾經是Wayne基金贊助的
used to be funded by The Wayne Foundation?
因為 資金停止了
Because the money stopped.
你也該出去轉轉了
About time to get some fresh air
好好瞭解下現在這個世界
and start paying attention to the details.
有些人可能正需要你的幫助
Some of that details might need your help.
你查了那個人嗎 貝恩
Have you checked that name, Bane?
他是僱傭兵 沒有名字
He's a mercenary. No names.
他和他的部下支持了西非的政變
He and he's man were behind a coup in West Africa.
他們從我們的朋友John Daggett那兒 得到了採礦許可
They've secured a mining operations for our friend, John Daggett.
-是Daggett帶他們來的 -看起來是的
- And Daggett brought them here. - So it seems.
-我會繼續查下去 -好的
- I'll keep digging. - Yeah.
Alfred 為什麼Wayne基金
Alfred, why did The Wayne Foundation
停止向城裡的孤兒院捐款了
stopped funding the boy's home in the city?
基金是從Wayne公司的利潤裡提成的
The foundation is funded by the profits of Wayne Enterprises.
肯定是有的
There have to be some ...
是時候跟Fox先生談談了
Time to talk to Mr. Fox I think.
我去打給他
I'll get him on the phone.
不用了 家裡還有車麼
No. Did we still have any car around the place?
有的 一兩輛
Yes, one or two
給我的腿預約個醫院
I need an appointment at a hospital for my leg.
-哪家醫院 -Jim Gordon住的那家
- Which hospital? - Which ever one Jim Gordon's in.
我看過更糟糕的軟骨
I've seen worst cartilage in knees.
-還不錯 -不
- It's a good? - No.
你膝蓋裡根本就沒有軟骨
That's because there's no cartilage in your knees
肘部和肩部的軟組織也有部分缺失
and not much of any use in your elbows or your shoulders.
除此之外 腎臟的舊傷
Between that and scar tissue on your kidney,
大腦也有震盪後的殘留損傷
residual concussive damage to your brain tissue
以及你渾身上下的大小傷
and the general scar over quality of your body,
我不建議你玩直升機滑雪哦 Wayne先生
I cannot recommend you to go heli-skiing, Mr. Wayne.
好的
Right.
我們是一起的 我以為你離開了
We're in this together. I thought you were gone.
人們不再需要蝙蝠了 我們贏了
The Batman wasn't needed anymore. We won...
我們撒了無數的謊
We strung a lie.
而現在罪惡又在我們試圖毀滅它的地方重新燃起
Now there's evil rises again where we try to bury him.
蝙蝠俠必須歸來
The Batman has to come back.
如果他已不復存在了呢
And if he doesn't exist anymore?
他必須回來
He must. You ...
錢包是你拿的 是吧
You got them wallet, do you?
-你偷了我的錢包 -不 我沒有
- You took my wallet! - No I didn't!
-滾開 -她偷我錢包
- Get out! - She took my wallet...
滾
Now!
瘋子
Crazy!
都不知道那麼緊張幹嘛 就60塊而已
I don't know why he's so upset about. It's only 60 bucks in here.
可能是擔心手錶吧
probably the watch.
那是誰
Who's that?
另一個爬不出跑車的老爺爺
Another stiff convety climb out of his sport car.
是Bruce Wayne
Well that's Bruce Wayne!
Bruce Wayne 看這裡
Bruce Wayne, over here!
-我不確定我的助理
- I'm not sure if my assistant ...
-這邊請 Wayne先生
- Right through here, Mr. Wayne.
多謝了
Thank you so much.
Bruce Wayne驚現慈善舞會
Bruce Wayne at a charity ball?
Tate小姐 是吧
Ms. Tate, is it not?
就算在你閉關以前 你也很少參加這種活動
Even before you became a recluse, you never came to these events.
油水都流回富人身上了
Proceeds goes to big fat spread.
這才不是慈善舞會
This is not about charity.
這只不過是哪個社交魔女依賴的野心食量而已
It's about feeding the ego which ever society hag laid this on.
實際上 這是我的舞會 Wayne先生
Actually this is my party, Mr. Wayne.
所得善款會得其所用
And the proceeds will go where they should,
因為油水都是我自掏腰包的
because I paid for the big fat spread myself.
那你油水流的很慷慨嘛
You spread generously?
這世界上 想要有所收穫就要有所投資嘛
You have to invest if you want to restore balance to the world.
接受我們的清潔能源企劃
Take our clean energy project.
有時 付出並不一定有回報
Sometimes, the investments just doesn't pay off.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
Wayne 你的冷漠只是一張面具
You have a practiced absent, Mr. Wayne.
要是一個人根本不關心
But a man who does not care
這個世界的話 是不會花掉一半身家
about the world doesn't spend half his fortune
去拯救它的
on a plan to save it.
而且也不會在失敗後那麼消沉從此隱退
And isn't so wounded when it's fail but he goes into hiding
玩的愉快 Wayne先生
Have a good evening, Mr. Wayne!
介意我接手麼
Mind if I cut in?
多謝
Thank you.
見到我好像沒有很開心哦
You're don't seem happy to see me.
-你應該在閉關才對 -突然想呼吸新鮮空氣了呢
- You're suppose to be a shut-in. - I felt like some fresh air.
為什麼不叫警察
Why didn't you called the police?
我有一個神奇的朋友專門處理這種問題
I have a powerful friend who deals with things like these.
一個穿著釬焊服裝的飛賊
It's a brazing costume for a cat burglar.
-是麼 那你又是誰啊
- Yeah? Who are you pretending to be?
-Bruce Wayne 古怪的大富翁啊
- Bruce Wayne, eccentric billionaire.
-你舞伴是誰 -他老婆在Ibiza
- Who's your date? - His wife is in Ibiza.
她把鑽石都留在家裡了 怕被偷走呢
She left her diamonds behind though, worried it might get stolen.
是Ibitha
It pronounced 'Ibitha'.
你不會希望他們中有人
You wouldn't want any of
發現你是個賊吧
these folks realizing you're a crook
而不是什麼社交名媛
not a Social planner.
你以為我在乎別人怎麼看我嗎
You think I care what everyone in this rooms thinks of me?
我打賭你在乎每個人對你的每一種看法
I doubt you care anyone in any room who thinks of you.
別自以為是了 Wayne先生 你根本就不瞭解我
Don't candescent, Mr. Wayne. You don't know me a thing about me.
是麼 Selina Kyle
Well Selina Kyle.
我知道你住在舊城區
I know you came here from your walk-out Old Town,
對珠寶賊來說也太節儉了
a modest place for a master jewel thief.
也就是說 你要麼是在為退休攢錢
Which means that either you're saving for retirement
要麼就是你了大麻煩
or you in deep with the wrong people.
別以為你生在Wayne家老宅的主臥
You don't get to judge me just because you
就有資格對我指指點點
were born the master bedroom of Wayne....
實際上 我生在酒店的套房裡
Actually, I was born in the Regency room.
我別無選擇
I started out doing what I had to.
一旦你開始做必須要做的事
Once you're done what you had to,
人們就不允許你再做你想做的事
They never let you do what you wanted to.
重新開始
Start fresh.
現在這個世界哪還有重新開始
There's no fresh start in today's world.
隨便一個12歲小朋友用手機都能查到你的平生
Any 12 years old with a cell phone would find out what you did.
我們做的任何事都留在檔案裡 無法擺脫
Everything we do is collated and quantified everything sticks.
你就是這麼為自己的偷竊辯解的?
Is that how you justify stealing?
我從富人身上拿走我需要的
I take what I need from those who have more than enough.
絕對不會拿窮人的東西
I don't stand on the shoulders of the people with less.
俠盜羅賓漢喲?
Robin Hood?
我覺得我幫助的人
I think I do more to help
比這房裡的大多數人都多
someone than most of the people in this room.
比你多
Than you.
我覺得 可能是你想太多了
I think maybe you're assuming a little too much.
我覺得 可能是你對你褲襠裡除了錢以外的
Maybe you're being unrealistic about what's
其它某些東西太過自信了
really in your pants other than wallets.
哎喲
Ouch.
你以為會一直這樣歌舞昇平嗎
You think all this can last?
暴風雨就要來了 Wayne先生
There's a storm coming, Mr. Wayne.
你和你朋友最好準備準備
You and your friends better battered down the hatches.
因為風暴一來 你們就會意識到
Because when it hits, you're all going to wonder
你們曾以為自己能窮奢極欲
you could ever thought you could live so large
不管他人的死活是有多天真
and leave so little for the rest of us.
聽起來你似乎很期待暴風雨的來臨
You sound like you're looking forward to it.
我適應力很強的
I'm adaptable.
這條項鏈戴在你身上確實很好看
Those pearls do look better on you than it did in my safe,
但我還是需要拿回去
but I still can't let you keep them.
你嚇跑她了
You scared her off!
才怪
Not likely ...
我把停車票丟了
I still lost my ticket.
你太太說你會打車回家的
Your wife said you're taking the cab home.
我太太
My wife?
就你一個 少爺
Just you, sir?
別擔心 Wayne少爺
Don't worry, Master Wayne.
情場鬼見愁 也要花點時間重新適應的
Takes a little time to get back in the swing of things.
Bruce Wayne 見到你真是讓人吃驚
Bruce Wayne! Design, live and breathe
是什麼把你從冬眠中喚醒的 Wayne先生
What brings you out of prior sleep, Mr. Wayne?
看來你還沒丟掉你的幽默感
I see you haven't lost your sense of humor,
即使你丟掉了我不少錢
even if you have lost most of my money.
事實上 是你自己弄丟的
Actually you did that.
如果你將整個研發部門的經費
If you follow all your entire RND budget
投入到能源計劃裡 又閒置它
to a fusion project that you get mock more.
你的公司是不可能掙錢的
Your company is unlikely to thrive.
我有什麼選擇
What are the options?
你依然堅持不啟動那台機器嗎
Well if you're not unwilling to turn on the machine,
不能 不能啟動 Lucius.
I can't. I can't, Lucius.
那麼 還是先坐好吧
Well then sit tight.
你陷入了困境
Your majority keep dagger at bay
當我們和Miranda Tate
while we figured out a
為能源項目構想未來的時候
future for the energy program with Miranda Tate.
她一直很支持這個項目
She has supported the project all the way.
她既聰明又可愛
She's smart and quite lovely.
我們都是為了你好 Bruce
We all just want what's best for you, Bruce.
- 給她看看那機器 - 我考慮一下
- Show her the machine. - I think it over.
- 還有其他事嗎 - 沒了 怎麼
- Anything else? - Nope. Why?
我們的談話一向已非尋常的要求告終
Well these conversation used to end with an unusual request.
我退隱了
I retired.
不管怎樣 我給你看些東西
Let me show you some stuff, anyway.
就當憶想當年吧
Just for old times' sake.
我以為你不得不關閉這裡
I figured you had to shut this place down.
官方記錄上 它一直是關閉著的
Oh, it was always shut down. Officially.
什麼新玩意兒
What's the new stuff ...
你父親去世後
After your father died, Wayne Enterprises
韋恩集團成立了14個不同的國防裝備子公司
has set up 14 different defense subsidiaries.
多年來我嘗試著把所有的原型機
For years, I've been shuttering and consolidating
集中到一個屋簷下
all the different prototypes under one roof.
- 我的屋簷 - 為什麼
- My roof. - Why?
為了不讓它們落入惡人手中
Keep them from falling into the wrong hands.
現在你簡直是在炫耀了
Now you just showing off.
這是個國防項目
It's a defense department project.
用於精確的區域鎮壓
Tight Geometer Urban Pacification.
旋翼的設計讓其能
Rotors are configured to maneuver between buildings
在建築中自由穿行
without recirculation.
它叫什麼
What it's call?
有一個又長又無聊的韋恩集團命名
It has a long uninteresting Wayne Enterprise』s designation.
我只想稱它為蝙蝠
I just the took of calling it The Bat.
是的 Wayne先生 有一款黑色的
And yes Mr. Wayne, it does come in black.
運行穩定 只是沒有自動駕駛系統
Works fine, except for the autopilot.
只有等比我智商更高的人添上去了
Takes a better mind than mine to fix it.
比你智商還高的人
A better mind?
我只是謙虛一下
Well I was trying to be modest.
至少不那麼忙的人 比如說你
A less busy mind, yours.
看起來會有點痛
It should be a bit painful.
你可以試試 Alfred
You'll be very welcome to try, Alfred.
我看著就好了 謝謝你 先生
Happy watching. Thank you, sir.
不錯
Not bad ...
是相當不錯
Not bad at all!
如果你真想重出江湖
If you're seriously considering going back out there,
你應該聽聽一些關於Bane的傳言
you should hear the rumors surrounding Bane.
洗耳恭聽
I'm all ears.
在一處古老的地方 有這麼個監獄
There is a prison in a more ancient part of the world.
人們被扔進這個地獄遭受苦難 等待死亡
A pit where men are thrown to suffer and die.
但是有一天 一個人從這片黑暗中一躍而出
But sometimes a man rises from the darkness.
有一天 那地獄送了一些東西回人間
Sometimes, the pit sends something back.
- Bane - 沒錯
- Bane! - Right.
在人間煉獄中 他出生長大
Born and raised in hell on earth.
生於監獄
Born in a prison?
沒人知道他是怎麼逃出來的
No one knows why or how he escaped.
但他們知道他逃出來後
But they do know once he did,
他在忍者大師門下磨煉 你的師傅
he was trained by Ra's Al Ghul, your mentor.
Bane是 影武者聯盟 中的一員
Bane was a member of The League of Shadows.
後來他被逐出了聯盟
And then he was excommunicated.
如果有人讓忍者大師都覺得太過極端
And any man who is too extreme for Ra's Al Ghul,
絕不容輕視
is not to be trifled with.
我可不是以輕視罪犯的聞名的
I didn't realized I was known for trifling with criminals.
此一時彼一時
That was then.
現在你可以綁好你的腿 重新戴上面具
Then you can just strap up your leg and put your mask back on,
但這不代表你回到了當年的狀態
but that doesn't make you what you were.
如果這個人有你說的一半厲害
If this man is everything what you say he is,
那麼這個城市需要我
then the city needs me.
這城市需要Bruce Wayne 你的資源 你的學識
The city needs Bruce Wayne, your resources, your knowledge.
而不是你的身體和生命
It doesn't need your body or your life.
那個時代已經過去
That times has past.
你是怕我出去後 會失敗嗎
You're afraid if I go back out there, I'll fail.
不是
No.
我是怕你想那樣
I'm afraid that you want to.
如果Bruce Wayne參加宴會 股票就會下跌
You can't short the stock if Bruce Wayne goes to a party.
Wayne的回歸使股市震盪
Wayne's coming back has change.
這是好事還是壞事 - 我想是壞的
- Changes, is it good or bad? - I vote bad.
- 憑什麼 - 拋硬幣
- On what basis? - I flip the coin.
我說了不要全麥麵包
I said no rye man.
小伙子 請卸下頭盔 我們這需人臉監控
Rookie! Loose the helmet! We need faces for camera.
來吧 我們去掠奪
Come on let's go scalping.
這是股票交易中心 沒有錢給你搶
This is a stock exchange. There's no money you can steal.
真的嗎 那你們這幫人在這幹嘛
Really? Then why are you people here?
你必須要進去
You got to get in there!
- 有人被劫持了嘛 - 不是 這是個搶劫案
- It's a hostage situation. - No! This is a robbery!
他們直接進入了在線交易平台
They have direct access to the online trading desk.
我不會為了你們的錢而讓我的人冒險
I'm not risking my men for your money.
先生 你要離開這裡 我們在辦案
Sir, you going to ask you to move. We have a situation here.
不是我們的錢 是每個人的
It's not our money, it's everybody's.
真的嗎 我的錢都在床墊裡
Really? Mine is in my mattress.
如果不把這些人拿下
If don't put these guys down,
那麼在你床墊裡的錢 就會變得分文不值
that something in your mattress maybe be worth a whole hell of a lot less.
切斷光纖電纜 毀了那個基站
Cut the fiber cable and take out that cell tower.
- 謝謝你 - 那會拖住他們
- Thank you. - That will slow them down.
他們切斷了光纖
They cut the Fiber.
- 基站還在工作 - 現在而已
- The cell's working. - For now.
把這些障礙都立起來
Get all this barriers up.
全給我立起來
I want all of them up.
這幾條街上不許任何人進出
No one gets in or out of any of these streets.
- 我能轉移到哪去 - 退一下
- Where am I suppose to move it? - Back it up.
呆在車裡別出來 好嗎
Just stay in your vehicle, okay?
程序還需要多少時間
How much longer does the program needs?
8分鐘
Eight minutes.
我們該撤了
Time to go move out.
每個人都站起來
Everybody up!
你們兩個 走
You two, move!
謝謝
Thank you.
穩住
Steady!
鎖定目標了
I got something!
不要開槍 有人質
Do not shoot! We've hostages!
大家不要開槍
Hold your fire!
快 快
Go! Go!
嘿 放我走
Hey, let me go!
求求你 喂
Please! Hey!
- 射輪胎 - 不能射
- Shoot the tires! - There's no shot.
往後退 往後退 他們有人質
Now back off! Back off! They've got hostages!
警方正在市中心追捕
Police are pursuing the 4 suspects from
4個挾持人質的罪犯
downtown in respond to a hostage situation
哥譚警局
Gotham PD...
燈怎麼滅了
What's going on with the lights?
我什麼都看不見
I can't pick up anything!
那他媽的誰啊
Who the hell was that?
孩子 今晚有好戲看了
Oh boy you're in for a show tonight, son!
救命啊
Please! Help!
對不起
Sorry!
在你傷到自己前把這玩意兒放下
Put that thing away before you hurt yourself.
上車
Get in!
我們走吧 你 快上車
Let's go. You, get in the car!
我們發現蝙蝠俠了
We've spotted The Batman!
大家都行動起來
I want all everyone in.
所有的巡邏車 街頭刑警 下班的
Every car patrol, street cops and off duty too.
讓他們趕緊行動
Call them in now!
我要做Jim Gordon沒有做到的事
I'm going to do what Jim Gordon never could.
- 什麼事 - 我要抓住蝙蝠俠
- What's that? - I'm going to take down The Batman.
4個嫌疑犯正劫持著
..The 4 suspect are carrying two hostages
在哥譚股票交易中心綁架的兩名人質
that they kidnapped them at the Gotham Stock Exchange.
目擊證人稱
Witnesses reported that ...
似乎難以置信
It seems hard to believe.
但是據報道疑犯正在被
But report are suspects are now being pursued,
蝙蝠俠追趕
what appears to be, The Batman.
好吧 這多難說
Well what do you know..
老大 那些劫匪怎麼辦
Sir, what about the armed robbers?
求求你 放我走吧 求求你了
Please! Let me go! Please!
一輛摩托車已經停下了
One bike has pulled off.
沒有人質了 我們還追捕嗎
No hostage. Shall we pursue?
別追了 在這兒等蝙蝠俠
Negative. Stay on The Batman!
- 劫犯要逃走了 - 你想抓哪一個
- He's getting away. - Who do you want to catch huh?
幾個搶劫犯還是殺了Harvey Dent的那個狗娘養的傢伙
Some robber or the son-of-a-bitch who killed Harvey Dent?
8年了 他非要選今晚出現
Eight years and he has to pick tonight.
他把警察從Bane身上引開了
He's drawing the cops off Bane.
求求你 就放我走吧 求求你
Please! Just let me go! Please!
完成傳送
Transferring complete
他跑了
We lost him.
你們是怎麼讓他跑了的
How could you lose him?
他火力充足
He's got a lot of firepower.
那又怎麼樣 你們不充足嗎
And what? You don't?
他折回市區了
He heads back downtown.
他跟他的穿著一樣傻
and he's as dumb as he dresses.
包圍上 夥計們
Close it up, gentlemen!
他簡直是落籠的老鼠 夥計們
Like a rat in a trap, gentlemen!
這好像不是老鼠吧 老大
It might've the wrong animal there, sir!
你確定是他嗎
You're sure it was him?
Bane說蝙蝠俠介入了 但任務仍圓滿完成
Bane says that Batman interfered, but the task was accomplished.
那他們逮捕的人呢
What about the men they've arrested?
我引用他的原話 他們死也不會開口的
He said and I quote: ' They would die before talking. '
他在哪找的這些人
Where does he finds these guys?
開香檳
Open the champagne!
我們能叫幾個妞來嗎
And can we get some girls in here?
你確定你消受得了
Be careful what you wish for!
- 貓吃了你的舌頭嗎 - 你這蠢女人
- Cat got your tongue? - You dumb bitch!
從沒人罵過我蠢
Nobody ever accuse of being dumb.
今晚來這兒 你的確是個蠢貨
You're dumb, for coming here tonight.
我要拿回你欠我的
I want what you owe me.
- 你不會得到的 - 裝備不錯
- One doesn't get ... - Nice outfit!
穿著高跟鞋走路不會不方便嗎
Aren't those heels make it tough to walk?
我不知道 你說呢
I don't know, do you think?
- 它在哪裡 - 什麼在哪裡
- So where is it? - Where's what?
「清洗程序」
The program ' The Clean Slate '.
為有犯罪記錄的超級大盜設計的終極程序
The Ultimate Tool for a master thief with a record.
不許動
Hold it right there!
- 在哪裡 - 「清洗程序」嗎
- Where is it?! - ' The Clean Slate? '
當你輸入一個人的名字 出生日期
When you type in someone's name, date of birth
幾分鐘後所有相關數據都消失了
and a few minutes they're gone, every database on earth.
聽起來美好得不真實
Sounds a little too good to be true?
你在說謊 RIKEN數據已做到試運行階段了
You're lying! RIKEN DATA took it to the prototype stage.
所以我買他們
That's why I bought them.
但是他們什麼都沒有 不過是個傳說
But they had nothing. It was a gang-land myth.
往後退
Stay back!
我不是在虛張聲勢
I'm not bluffing!
他們知道 它們只是不在乎
They know! They just don't care.
- 你耍我吧 - 不用槍 不殺人
- You got to be kidding me. - No guns, no killing.
那有什麼樂趣
Where the fun in that?
我媽媽提醒過我不要隨便上陌生人的車
My mother warned about getting into cars with strange men.
這不是車
This isn't a car.
回見
See you around!
不用謝
You're welcome!
- 我能控制局勢 - 他們不是街頭暴徒
- I had it under control. - Those weren't street thugs.
他們是訓練有素的殺手 我救了你的命
They were trained killers. I saved your life.
作為回報 我想知道
In return, I need to know
你為什麼要偷Bruce Wayne的指紋
what you did with Bruce Wayne's fingerprints.
Wayne說他有個厲害的朋友 看來不是撒謊
Wayne wasn't kidding about a powerful friend.
我把他指紋賣給了Daggett
I sold his prints to Daggett.
為了些一些子虛烏有的目的
Something that doesn't even exist.
我以為你不會這麼容易上當
I doubt that will get the better of you.
當一個女孩走途無路時
Hey when a girl's desperate...
他用指紋做什麼
What's he going to do with them?
我不知道 但是Daggett
I don't know but Dagget seem pretty
似乎對股票市場發生的混亂很感興趣
interested in that mess at the stock market.
Kyle小姐
Miss Kyle ...
原來這就是被甩的感覺
So that's what that feels like...
我在新聞報道中看見你了
I seen you in the television coverage,
你已嘗到了重回街頭的感覺了吧
you've got your taste for wanting destruction back.
這兒有三張磁盤
There are 3 disks.
不該讓警方調查嗎
Aren't the police suppose to be investigating them?
他們沒有工具能分析它
They don't have the tools to analyze it.
你捐給他們就好了
They would if you gave it to them.
一人的工具會成為另一人的武器
One man's tool is another man weapon.
在你看來也許是
In your mind perhaps,
但不能被變成武器的東西本就沒多少
but there aren't many things can't turn into a weapons.
Alfred 夠了 警方沒能追住他們
Alfred, enough! The police weren't getting it done
也許他們會呢
Perhaps they might have.
如果你沒有做餘興表演的話
If you hadn't made the side show of yourself.
我才沒有
You I didn't had it in me.
你有 你要在警察面前表現自己
No! You got to glow at the police force, a married chased
還迷戀於Fox那來的一些花俏新玩具
with a lot of fancy new toys from Fox's.
當你哪天遇到他又怎麼辦
What about when you come up against him?
那時候
What then?
更努力地戰鬥 我一直都這樣
I'll fight harder. I always have.
看看 他的速度 他的兇猛 他的技巧
Take a look, his speed, his ferocity, his training.
我看見了信念的力量
I see the power of believe.
我看見了影武者聯盟的影子
I see The League of Shadows insurgent.
- 你說他被逐出聯盟了 - 被忍者大師
- You said he was excommunicated. - By Ra's Al Ghul.
現在誰在領導他們
Who leads them now?
忍者大師是影武者聯盟的首領 我打敗了他
Ra's Al Ghul was The League of Shadows and I beat him.
Bane只是個僱傭兵 我們要找出他的真實目的
Bane is just a mercenary, we need to find out what he's up to.
類似某種交易 編碼的
Trade of some kind. Coded.
Selina Kyle竊取了我的指紋
And my fingerprints courtesy of Selina Kyle.
把這給Fox
Give this to Fox.
他能破解密碼
He can crack the code
告訴我們他們在進行什麼交易
and tell us what trades they were executing.
我會把這交給Fox先生但是不會再有下次了
I'll give this to Mr. Fox but no more.
我看著你出生 服侍你長大 但我不想埋葬你
I sewed you up, I set your bums but I wont bury you.
Wayne家族成員的死我已經看得夠多了
I buried enough members in The Wayne family.
你要離我而去嗎
You're leaving me?
你固執的覺得自己只有一個未來
You see only one end to your journey.
為了讓你醒悟 我必須離開
Leaving is all I have to make you understand.
你再也不是蝙蝠俠了 你要尋找另一種生活方式
You're not Batman anymore. You have to find another way.
你曾經說過
You used to talked about
離開黑暗 過正常人的生活
finishing about a light on that awful cave.
Alfred, Rachel死之前我們已經決定在一起
Alfred, Rachel died knowing that we had decided to be together.
我曾有過機會過正常生活
That was my life, beyond the cave.
我現在依然沒辦法放下
I can't just move on.
她本應該得到更好的
She didn't, she couldn't have.
- 要是她已經得到了呢  - 你知道現在說什麼都晚了
- What did she had? - You know I can't change that.
如果 在她死之前 她寫了一封信
And if, before she died, she wrote a letter
信中說她選擇了Harvey Dent而不是你
saying she chose Harvey Dent over you?
而我為了減少你的痛苦
And what if to spare your pain....
燒掉了那封信
I burned that letter ...?
你怎麼敢用Rachel來阻擋我
How dare you use Rachel to try and stop me.
我習慣了選擇Wayne主人
I am using to choose Master Wayne.
也許是時候我們開始嘗試看清真相 就讓它這麼赤裸裸地呈現著
Maybe it's time we all start trying to out smart the truth and let it have it stay.
- 我很抱歉 - 你很抱歉
- I'm sorry. - You're sorry?
你想摧毀我的世界
You expect to destroy my world ...
然後你覺得我們就這樣握手言和嗎
... and then think we're going to shake hands?
不會
No.
- 我知道這代表了什麼 - 這代表了什麼
- I know what this means. - What is it means?
這代表了你對我的憎恨 和失去
It means your hatred and it also mean losing someone.
一個從他的第一聲啼哭迴響這房子裡
Who I've cared kept for since I first heard
我便在乎的人
his cries echoes through this house.
但這也許也意味著拯救你的生命
But it might also mean saving your life.
這才是更重要的
And that's more important.
再見 Alfred
Good bye, Alfred!
Alfred
Alfred?
- 你親自來開門啊 - 是啊
- Answering your own door? - Yeah.
第三頁
Page three.
看來你為公司的期貨交易
Seem you made a series a
做了一系列決定
laud of put options on the future exchange.
通過指紋驗證
Verified by thumb print.
這些期權自昨晚午夜起失效
Those options expired at midnight last night.
再多些時間我們也許能證明它是個騙局 但現在
Long term we may be able to prove it was a fraud but for now,
你徹底破產了
you're completely broke.
而Wayne集團
and Wayne Enterprises is
將會落入John Daggett之手
about to fall into the hands of John Daggett.
那些武器
The weapons ...
我們不能讓Daggett插手到那些武器中
We can't let Daggett get his hands on the applied sciences.
那些武器是完全對外封鎖 不入記錄的
Applied sciences is all lock up and off the books.
但能源項目又是另一回事了
The energy project however is a different story.
Miranda Tate
Miranda Tate ...
我們要說服董事會支持她
We need to convince the board to get behind her.
給她看看核反應堆
Let's show her the reactor.
我們在35分鐘內跟她在那兒會面 你最好穿戴好
We're meeting her there in 35 minutes so you better get dressed.
你帶我來這兒是給我看這個嗎 Fox先生
You brought me out here to show me this, Mr. Fox?
稍安勿躁 Tate小姐
Bear with me, Miss Tate.
請不要把手腳伸到車外
Please keep hands and feet in the car at all time.
就是這裡 對吧
This is it, isn't it?
核反應堆在河床下面
The reactor is beneath the river
這樣如果出了安全問題 就能立刻被河水淹沒
So it can be instantly flooded in an event of a security breach.
Bruce Wayne真的那麼疑神疑鬼嗎
Is Bruce Wayne really that paranoid?
對於這個問題 我保留意見
I fail to give an answer on that one.
你可能想知道你的投資都在什麼項目上
I thought you might like to see what your investment builds.
不用礦石燃料的清潔能源 能供給整個城市
No fossil fuels, free clean energy for an entire city!
三年前 有個俄羅斯的科學家發表了一篇論文
Three years ago, a Russian scientist published
內容是將熱核反應製成武器
a paper on weaponize fusion reactions.
一周之後 你的反應堆就開始出問題
One week later, your reactor started developing problems.
我覺得這機器是成功了才對
I think this machine works.
Miranda 如果這機器能夠正常運轉
Miranda, if it were operational,
才是對哥譚市最大的威脅
danger to Gotham would be too great.
那要是你聽說那個俄國科學家在半年前的
Would it make you feel better to know that the Russian
一次飛行事故中去世了會好受些嘛
scientist died in a plane crash six months ago?
總有人會和Pavel博士一樣努力研究
Someone been working hard with Dr. Pavel.
總有人會搞清楚如何把這能源
Someone will figured out the way for make
製成一個核武器
this power source into a nuclear weapon.
我要你來掌控韋恩集團和這個反應堆
I need you to take control of Wayne Enterprises and this reactor.
- 要用它做什麼? - 什麼都不做
- To do what with it? - Nothing.
- 除非我們能夠保證其安全性 - 那要是我們做不到呢
- Until we can guarantee it's safety. - And if we can't?
那就摧毀它 用水淹了
Decommission it, flood it.
要把這世界可能擁有的可持續能源的美好將來摧毀掉
Destroy the world's best chance for a sustainable future?
這個世界還沒有準備好使用這能源 所以是的
The world is not ready, yes.
Bruce 你要是想拯救世界
Bruce, if you want to
首先得要相信這個世界啊
save the world you have to start trusting it.
我不是信你麼
I'm trusting you.
這不算 你沒得選
It doesn't count. You have no choice.
我大可在過去的三年裡
I could've flooded this
直接淹了這能量室
chamber at any time in the last three years.
我選擇相信你 所以拜託
I choosing to trust you. Please ...
好了女士們先生們
Alright ladies and gentlemen,
這場會議該好好進行了
this meeting will now come to order.
我想先指出一下
You know, I would like to
我們這兒有一位非董事會的成員在座
point out that we have a non-board member here.
這太不合規矩了 即使說他的名字在門上的招牌裡
There is highly irregular, even if his name is above the door.
Bruce Wayne家族創立了這個企業
Bruce Wayne's family built this company.
- 而他自己也運營者它 - 他把公司給運營垮了 先生
- and he himself has run it ... - Into the ground, sir!
有誰不同意麼
Does anybody disagrees?
你們都去看看今早的股價
Check the share prices this morning.
對於未來的瘋狂投機不但耗掉了Wayne先生自己的職位
Crazy gambling on future not only cost Mr. Wayne his seat,
同樣還把好多我們的錢也一起賠進去了 所以他必須得離開
it has cost us all a lot of money and he has to go.
我恐怕他說得有道理 Wayne先生
I'm afraid he has a point, Mr. Wayne.
那我們說正題吧
Well back to business.
Wayne先生 重新做回一個普通人您感覺如何
How does it feel to be one of the people, Wayne?
Wayne先生 他們把您的車給拖走了
Mr. Wayne, they're towing your car..
我不知道你已經被踢出董事會了
I didn't know that you're off the board.
你看上去需要搭個車
Looks like you'll need a ride huh?
Wayne先生 你想要搭車麼
Mr. Wayne, will you get a ride?
那該死的Miranda Tate是怎麼
What the hell did Miranda Tate
打入Wayne集團董事會的
get the inside track on the Wayne Board?
她難道一直和他在見面
I mean, is she been meeting with him?
她是在和他上床嗎
Is she been sleeping with him?
就我們所知並沒有
Not that we know of.
得了吧 你根本也就不知道多少是吧 Bane在哪兒
Oh clearly you don't know much of anything, do you? Where's Bane?
- 你和他說過事關緊急了嗎 - 那他人在哪兒呢
- You told him it was urgent. - Where is that man now?
說曹操 曹操就到
Speak of the devil, and he shall appears.
這他媽都是怎麼回事
What the hell is going on?
一切正如計劃進行中啊
The plan is preceding as expected.
是麼 我看上去像是已經執掌Wayne集團的樣子嘛
Really? Do I look like I'm running Wayne Enterprises right now?
你襲擊了證券交易所 可那沒成功啊 我的朋友
Your hit on the stock exchange, it didn't work my friend.
然後現在你又讓我的工程隊
And now you have my construction crews
在城裡24小時到處開工
going around the city at 24 hours a day.
這到底算哪門子的幫助我吞掉Wayne集團呢
How exactly is that suppose to help my company absorbs Wayne?
- 退下 - 不用 你就待在這兒
- Leave us! - No! Stay here!
我才是這兒管事的人
I'm in charge here.
你覺得自己像麼
Do you feel in charge?
我可是給了你不少錢
I have paid you a small fortune.
所以你就以為自己可以壓過我了
And this gives you power over me?
你什麼意思
What is this?
你的錢還有工程隊起的作用真的很重要
Your money and infrastructure have been important ...
不過現在已經沒用了
... until now.
- 你到底是什麼東西 - 我就是哥譚市的審判日
- What are you? - I'm Gotham reckoning.
它會將你們所生活的一切終結
It'll end of all the damn you've been living on.
你太邪惡了
You are pure evil.
- 這是必要的嘛 - 不要
- A necessary evil. - No!
你惹了不小的麻煩
Well you've started quite a mess.
我只是要保護自己親近的人而已
To protect the people closes to me.
也許你的確是個獨行俠 你沒有家庭
Maybe you're a loner, right? You didn't have a family.
你還是有關心在乎的人啊
There are always people that you care about.
可你就是要等到他們都不見了才意識到這點
But you didn't realize how much until they're gone.
這只是一個象徵性的概念
The idea was to be a symbol.
任何人都可以是蝙蝠俠 那才是重點
Batman can be anyone. That was the point.
- 那他回來真是件大好事 - 可不是每個人都這麼想
- Well it damn good to see him back. - Not everybody agrees.
我最終會搞明白的
I'll figured that out in the end.
你查到Bane的行蹤了嘛
Do you got anything on Bane's whereabouts?
是啊 我手上有500頁的地下通道地圖和一把手電筒
Yes, I have 500 pages of tunnel records and a flashlight.
我真的很需要人幫忙
I could use some help actually.
這樣吧 你就在老城區那裡放我下車吧
You know what, drop me in the old town.
- 我不這麼想 - 這樣的話事情不會成功的
- I don't think so! - That is not how it works.
他不是目標
He's not a mark.
反正他的名號現在一分錢都不值
and he doesn't have a cent to his name anyway.
的確是不多 不過也總比你現在要好吧
Yeah. It's not much, but it's more than you got right now.
事實上 他們沒把我的房子收走
Actually, they're letting me keep the house.
有錢人就算是破了產還是和我們不一樣是吧
The rich doesn't even go broke like the rest of us huh?
我那個厲害的朋友希望你能回心轉意不要走
My powerful friend might hope to change your mind about leaving.
- 那他準備怎麼做 - 他準備把你想要的東西給你
- And how would he do that? - By giving you what you want.
- 那東西不存在 - 他說存在
- It doesn't exist. - He says it does.
- 他還說想在今晚和你見面 - 為什麼
- He wants to meet tonight. - Why?
他想找到Bane 然後說你知道怎麼找到他
He needs to find Bane. He says you know how.
- 告訴他我會考慮的 - 好的 我挺喜歡你這地方的
- Tell him I'll think about it. - Okay. I like your place.
Wayne先生
Mr. Wayne!
我很抱歉他們把你的錢都奪走了
I'm sorry they took all your money.
不 你才不抱歉
No you're not.
- 我們有什麼能幫到你麼警官 - 有啊
- Can we help you officer? - Yeah.
在一小時前John Daggett的屍體在一個垃圾箱裡被找到了
John Daggett's body was found in a dumpster an hour ago.
我以為你會想知道
Thought you might wanna know.
為什麼
Why?
因為在哥譚市半數的隧道許可證上
Well his name is all over this permit I just
全都有他的名字
pulled to half the tunnel under Gotham.
都是些交通維護 下水道建設還有其他的事由
That's MTA maintenance, sewer construction and others things...
你從這隧道裡研究出什麼來了
What did you get with the tunnel searches?
提醒我得把這愣頭青給踢走
Remind me to tell detail to keep hot heads out.
我們在那下面有一隊人 那是一個龐大的網絡
We had teams down there. It's a huge network.
那再多派些人
Well get more then.
就走這條線索 我要找到他
Work the grid. I want him found.
是的 那個面具男 我們這就去
Yeah, the masked man. We're on it.
把制服脫了 你現在跟我了
Lose the uniform. You』re working for me now.
我們現在可是需要些愣頭青
We could some hot head around here.
長官 Daggett的死因不會只是個巧合
Sir, Daggett's death could only be a coincidence.
你現在是個警探了孩子
You're a detective now, son.
已經不能再相信巧合這種事情的存在了
You're not allowed to believe in coincidences anymore.
- 沒人應門 - 沒有
- Nobody's answering. - No ...
- 現在就我一個人了 - 你有鑰匙麼
- I'm on my own now. - Do you have keys?
我從來沒使用過
I never needed them.
我希望你不介意用我的錢
I hope you didn't liked reaching my money.
要遭這樣的罪
Suffering this character.
Bruce 我會好好照管你父母的心血
I'll take care of your parents legacy, Bruce.
是誰
Who's this?
Alfred去哪兒了
Where is Alfred?
他走了
He left.
還把所有東西都
...taking everything...
- 那是什麼 - 我們剛剛好像斷電了
- What's that? - Our power has been shut off.
你很會生火啊
You're good at that.
我小時候 家裡一貧如洗
When I was a child, we had almost nothing.
可每當夜晚我們生起火 就會覺得好像無比富有
But on the nights when we had a fire, We felt very rich indeed...
我原以為你家境殷實
I assumed your family was wealthy.
我小時候那會兒還沒有
Not always not when I was young.
- 那是個老錯了 - 我自己也犯過
- It's an old mistake. - I had a few myself.
還不止一兩個
More than a few.
我們可以今晚就走
I could leave tonight.
坐我的飛機去我們想去的地方
Take my plane and go anywhere we wanted.
也許等將來哪天吧 今晚不行
Some day perhaps. Not tonight.
別害羞啊
Don't be shy!
Wayne說你可以把"清洗程序"給我
Wayne said that you can get me the 'Clean Slate'.
- 那要看 - 看什麼
- That depends ... - On what?
看你想用它做什麼事
On what you want it for..
我要確保它不會落入錯誤之手
I have acquire it to keep it out of the wrong hands.
還是不信任我是吧
Still don't trust me huh...
- 我們要怎麼改變這點呢 - 就從帶我去見Bane開始
- How can we change that? - Start by taking me to Bane.
是你要求的
You asked...
從這裡開始 Bane的人會巡查隧道
From here, Bane's man patrol the tunnels
而他們可不是你平時打架消遣的對象
and they're not your average brawlers.
我也不是
Neither am I.
- 他在你後面 - 誰
- He's behind you! - Who?
我
Me!
你以為自己在往哪兒走
Where do you think you're going? ...
別這麼霸氣
Less a little bully.
我總要想辦法不讓他們殺了我吧
I had to find a way to stop them trying to kill me.
你犯了一個嚴重的錯誤
You made a serious mistake.
恐怕沒有你犯的
Not as serious as yours ...
要嚴重
... I fear.
- Bane - 我們可別就這麼站著啊
- Bane ... - Let's not stand on so moody here.
Wayne先生
Mr. Wayne ...
平靜削弱你
Peace has cost you your strength.
勝利擊垮你
Victory has defeated you.
這些謊言欺詐
The adaptability and deception ...
只能蒙蔽那些無知的人
powerful agents ... to the uninitiated people.
只有我們心知肚明 不是麼 Bruce
But we are initiated aren't we, Bruce?
我們都是影武者聯盟的一員
Members of the League of Shadows.
可你背叛了我們
And you betrayed us.
是啊 你被一群精神變態們給驅逐了
Yes. You were excommunicated by a gang of psychopaths.
我 就是影武者
I am the League of Shadows.
我來到這裡是為了完成忍者大師的遺志
I'm here to fulfill Ra's Al Ghul's destiny!
你打起來倒像是個年輕人 完全不留後路
You fight like a younger man, there's nothing held back.
很可敬 不過也是個錯誤
It's admirable, but mistaken.
你以為黑暗是站在你一邊的嗎
You think darkness is your ally?
你僅僅只是適應了黑暗 而我是因黑暗而生
You've merely adopted the dark, I was born in it.
由黑暗而鑄
Molded by it ...
直到成年以後 我才得見天日
I didn't see the light until I was already a man.
但我只覺得光明很刺眼
By then was nothing to be blinded.
暗影背棄了你 是因為他們屬於我
Shadows betray you because they belong to me!
讓我來告訴你我是以何處為家的吧
I'll show you where I had made my home.
在準備著審判之時
Whilst preparing to bring justice.
我會擊潰你
Then I will break you.
你那珍貴的軍庫 我就不客氣的收下了
Your precious armory! Great fully accepted.
我們會需要用到的
We'll need it.
啊是的 我一直在好奇是哪一樣東西會更先崩潰
Ah yes! I was wondering what would weight first...
是你的精神
Your spirit ...
還是你的肉體
... or your body?
請給我接Gordon局長
Get me Commissioner Gordon.
關於議員被綁一案我有了一條線索
I got a line up of Congressman's kidnapping.
- 不好意思 小姐 - 什麼
- Excuse me, miss! - Yes?
我需要檢查您的機票和證件
I'm going to need to see your ticket and identification, please.
不介意幫我拿下嗎
Do you mind?
我把你的照片給議員看了 猜猜怎麼著
I showed your picture to The Congressman. Guess what?!
- 不要告訴我 他還想著我 - 神魂顛倒
- Don't tell me. Still in love? - Oh head over heels.
不過還是準備起訴你
Pressing charges though.
你犯了些錯啊 Kyle小姐
You've made some mistakes, Miss Kyle.
- 姑娘家也要討生活嘛 - 喲你胃口可真好
- Girl's got to eat. - And you have an appetite.
為什麼要逃 你這樣的犯罪記錄是逃不掉的
Why would run? You can't hide from us with a record like this.
- 也許我不是在躲你呢 - 那你在躲誰 Bane嘛
- Maybe it's not you I'm running from. - Who then? Bane?
你對他瞭解多少
What do you know about him?
我只知道你應該像我一樣害怕他
About you should be as afraid of him as I am.
我們可以給你提供保護
We can offer you protection.
好吧
Okay ...
我發現你的時候 其實
When I spotted you,
我是在找我的一個朋友 Bruce Wayne
I was looking for a friend of mine, Bruce Wayne.
他死了嗎
Did that killed him?
我不確定
I'm not sure.
為什麼不直接殺了我
Why didn't you just kill me?
你不怕死 你渴望死亡
You don't fear death, you welcome it.
你會在這裡接受懲罰
Your punishment must be mastered here.
- 你要慢慢折磨我 - 是的
- torture? - Yes.
但不是折磨你的身體
But not of your body.
而是你的靈魂
Of your soul.
- 我在哪兒 - 家
- Where am I? - Home.
在這兒我領悟了什麼是真正的絕望 你也會的
Where I learned the truth about despair, as will you.
這個監獄被稱為人間地獄是有原因的
There's a reason why this prison were a hell on earth.
希望
Hope.
幾個世紀以來
Every man who has lotted
每個收押於此的犯人抬頭看著亮光
here over the centuries looked up to the light
想像著攀向自由
and imagine climbing to freedom.
多容易 多簡單
So easy, so simple!
除非有的人
Unless you break man
真的一蹶不振
turning into seawater for uncontrollably fast.
很多人死於嘗試
Many have died trying.
沒有希望就沒有真正的絕望
And then here can be no true despair without hope.
所以在我恐嚇哥譚的同時
So as I terrorize Gotham,
我會用希望毒害他們的靈魂
I will feed it's deeper hole to poison their souls.
我會讓他們相信他們能活下去
I would let them live so they can survived
這樣你就能看著他們自相殘殺
and you can watch them trampling over each other
只為了一絲生的希望
... to stay in the sun.
你能目睹我折磨著整個城市
You could watch me torturing an entire city.
等你真正明白你有多麼失敗的時候
And then when you truly understood the depth of your failure,
我們會完成忍者大師的使命
we will fulfill Ra's Al Ghu's destiny.
我們會毀滅哥譚
We will destroy Gotham.
你會親眼目睹哥譚化為灰燼 無能為力
and then, what would you've done, when Gotham is ashes ...
那時 我才准許你死
Then you have my permission to die.
你要把她關在這兒?
You're locking her up in here?
丹特法案允許某些特殊情況下男女無需隔離
The Dent's act allowed non-segregation based extraordinary needs.
她第一次逃出女子勞教所時才16歲
First time she broke out of women correctional, she was 16.
- 靠近點兒 甜心 - 怎麼了甜心 你想牽我的手嗎
- A little closer, honey! - Why honey? You want to hold my hand?
她沒事的
She's going to be fine.
我還是不明白
I still don't see the need
為什麼董事會要為了能源項目開會
of a board meeting for the energy project.
Bruce做過很多正確的事
Bruce got a lot of things right,
把董事會瞞在鼓裡可不是其中之一
keeping the board in the dark was not one of them.
哦 你能來加入我們真好 主席
Oh good of you to join us Chair President.
現在我只需要再來個常任董事會成員就夠了
All I need now is one more Ordinary Board member.
- Fox先生 你想提名嗎 - 不 我自願
- Mr. Fox, would you like to nominate? - No. I will volunteer.
你要把我們帶到哪兒去
Where are you taking us?
你是對的 局長
You were right, Commissioner!
可以讓我們單獨談談嗎
Would you excuses us, please?
發生了什麼
What happened?
你那些面具男綁架了韋恩集團的董事會
Your mask man kidnapped the Wayne Enterprise's Board.
他把大部分人放走了
He let most of them go,
但帶了三個去下水道
but he took three of them into the sewers.
別再巡邏了 別再玩捉迷藏了
No more patrols. No more hide and seek.
把每個能用的警察都召集起來 全力抓他
Get every available cop down there and smoke him out.
- 市長不想製造恐慌的 - 那就說是演習
- The Mayor won't want panic. - So it's a training exercise?
我很抱歉我之前沒有相信你
I'm sorry I didn't take you seriously.
你別走 你告訴我蝙蝠俠已不在
Not you, you telling me The Batman have gone.
那麼你就去用盡一切辦法追查蛛絲馬跡
So you chase up the daggers leads anyway you can.
遵命 長官
Yes, sir.
他問 你付多少錢求我們殺了你
He asks how you much would pay us to let you die?
我跟他說 我跟他說你身無一物
I told him...I told him you have nothing.
你跟他說 我求之不得
You tell them pleasure!
有人付給我更多錢來保你活命
he paid more than that to keep you alive.
你會試著爬出去
You would try to climb.
他能成功嗎 每個人都會嗎
He can win? Everybody has?
當然不是了
Well of course not!
他說有一個曾經爬了出去
He say there's one who did.
一個孩子
A child.
一個生於地獄的孩子
A child born in this hell.
- Bane - 那只是一個古老的傳說罷了
- Bane ... - An old legend. Nothing more.
給我說說
Tell me
看看電視吧 你關心的事馬上就要開始了
What they really tease me, you wanted to see is happening soon.
爆破
Fire in the hole!
把它打開
Turn it on!
我只需要一個董事成員
I only need one other Board member,
還有八個等著呢
there are eight others waiting.
我不幹
I won't do it.
好了 停下
Alright stop!
Lucius 你這樣你們倆都得死
Lucius, you will kill this man and yourself,
也阻止不了他什麼
and you'll barely slow them down.
快點啊 該你上場了
Go on then, do your work!
帶他們到地面上去
Take them up to the surface!
他們這種地位的人有權體驗
People of their status deserve to experience
西方文明的新時代
the next era of Western civilization.
我掌握了一部分
I had half of daggett some of that plan some odd
Daggett地下工程中的可疑地點
location they pour for underground construction.
有蹊蹺嗎
anything strange about the pouring?
說實話 局長
Honestly, Commissioner.
我對土木工程不太瞭解
I don't know anything about civil engineering.
但你瞭解犯罪 繼續找
But knowing about patterns. Keep looking!
好了 現在這是個四百萬噸級的核彈了
It's done. This is now a 4 megatons nuclear bomb!
把核心從反應堆裡取出來
Pull the core out of the reactor!
不 你不能那麼做
No! You cannot!
這是維持它穩定的能量源
This is the power source capable of sustaining it.
如果你把它拿走 核心在幾個月內就會衰竭
If you move it, the core will depleted in a matter of months.
- 按我的計算 是五個月 - 它會爆炸的
- Five, by my calculations. - It will go off!
為了你孩子著想 帕維爾博士 我希望它真的會爆炸
And for the sake of your children Dr. Pavel, I did hope it does.
嘿
Hey
那天證券交易所門前的是你 是不是
That was you in front of The Stock Exchange wasn't it?
哪天
When?
就是一半的警察都試圖開進Castle街
When half the city cops try to pull onto castle street
而你的卡車把他們堵在外面的那天
and your truck was shutting them out.
- 哦是啊 你是那個警察 - 現在是警探了
- Oh yeah ... you're the cop. - Detective now
而作為警探 我不相信巧合
And, as detective we're not allowed to believe in coincidences.
你們在這裡做什麼 你們有什麼計劃
What were you doing here? What are you working on?
局長 我是Blake
Commissioner it's Blake.
我這兒有兩個死了的證人和一堆問題
I got two dead witnesses and a lot of questions.
務必給我回電話
Call me when ...
等等 四桶聚異丁烯
Wait a minute! Four barrels of polyisobutylene
旁邊好像是機油 天啊
That looks like motor oil right next to it. Jesus!
他們造的不是水泥 是炸彈
They're not making cement, they're making explosive!
- 給我接通Foley - Foley正在監察行動
- Patch me through Foley! - Foley is overseeing the operation.
他們正往火坑裡跳
They're heading into a trap.
我們看見上千名警察走進下水道
We seeing literally thousand of police heading into the sewer.
市長先生 上千名警察正
Mr. Mayor, literally thousands of police ...
這只是一次演練而已
It's just a training exercise that's all.
現在 若你不介意
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我還要拿著這兩張票去看我們的隊員完爆Rapid City隊呢
I got tickets to watch our boys trash Rapid City.
我是Foley
Foley.
那是陷阱 讓他們都出來
It's a trap. Pull all of them out!
貝恩一直在往水泥裡填炸藥
Bane has been pour concrete rigs with explosives.
在哪兒
Where?
環繞了整個地下隧道
There's a ring surrounding the tunnels!
他們會引爆炸藥 把警察全困在地下
They're going to blow it and trap the cops underground!
全部撤退 馬上
Pull them out! Now!
這聲音真好聽
That's a lovely lovely voice!
遊戲開始吧
Let the games begin!
讓市民們掌控
Citizens take control ...
掌控屬於你們的城市
Take control of your city!
- Foley - 天啊 Blake
- Foley! - Jesus, Blake!
城裡所有警察都在隧道裡
Every cop in the city is down in those tunnels!
不是所有警察
Not every cop.
先生 你還好嗎 我是警察
Sir, you're okay? I'm a police officer,
我現在要徵用你的車
I need your car right now.
開道吧 菜鳥
Play the corners, rookie!
去拿大衣 孩子
Get the coat, son!
這 這是奏響自由的號角
This, this is the instrument of your liberation.
衛星顯示放射性波動
Satellite show some radiation spike.
不管它是什麼 肯定是核能
Whatever it is, it's nuclear.
做個自我介紹吧
Identify yourself to the world!
Leonid Pavel博士 核物理學家
Dr Leonid Pavel, nuclear physicist.
Pavel已被確認死亡 在烏茲別克斯坦的墜機事件裡
Pavel was confirmed dead, plane crash on an agency pull out of Uzbekistan
但這看上去是他
but it looks like it's him.
那麼這個 這個又是什麼
And what, What is this?
這是個威力極大的中子彈 輻射半徑6英里
It's a fully prime neutron bomb with a blast radius of 6 miles.
那麼誰能解除這個裝置呢
And who is capable of disarming such a device?
只有我
Only me.
只有你 謝謝 好博士
Only you ... Thank you, good doctor!
現在 炸彈已經設定好了
Now, this bomb is armed.
這枚炸彈是可操縱的
This bomb is mobile and
而控制它的人的身份是個謎
the identity of the trigger man is a mystery.
引爆器就在你們當中的一個人手裡
For one of you holds the detonator.
現在 我們來這裡不是要征服 而是要解放
Now we came here not as conquerors, but liberators to
我們要把城市的控制權還給市民
return control of this city to the people.
只要一發現有外界干預
At the first sight of interference of the outside world,
或是有人試圖逃跑
or to those people attempting to flee,
這位匿名的哥譚市民
This anonymous Gotham-might,
這位沉默的英雄就會引爆炸彈
this unsung hero will trigger the bomb.
從現在開始 戒嚴管制生效
As of now, Martial Law is in effect.
回家吧
Return to your homes,
和你們的家人擁抱在一起等待
hold your families close and wait.
明天你們就知道什麼才真正屬於你
Tomorrow you claim what is rightfully yours.
撤回戰鬥機 派遣高級別偵察機
Hold back the fighters! Start high level reconnaissance flights.
給我連線總統
Get the president on the line!
坦克和飛機不能阻止我們引爆炸彈
Tanks and planes cannot stop us from detonating our device.
派個談判專家來商議支援與交流的條件
Send a negotiator to discuss term of access to supplies and communication!
你們有多少人 孩子
How many of you there, son?
你沒有足夠的人來阻止一千兩百萬人離開這所島嶼
You don't have enough man to stop 12 million people from leaving this island.
是的 我們沒有 但你們有
No, no we don't. But you do.
為什麼我們要幫你囚禁你的人質
Why the hell would I try help you to keep your hostages?
要是有一個人跨過這座橋 哥譚就會被炸飛
If one person crosses this bridge, Gotham gets blown to hell.
我們最偉大城市的居民是堅韌的
The people of our greatest city are resilient
他們證明過一次 也會證明第二次
They have proven this before and they will prove it again.
我們不和恐怖分子談判
We do not negotiate with terrorists,
但我們能認清事實
But we do recognize realities.
隨著情況不斷發展
As this situation develops,
有一件事必須明確
one thing must be understood above all others.
哥譚人民 我們沒有拋棄你們
People of Gotham, we have not abandoned you.
這是什麼意思
What does that mean?
意思就是我們得靠自己了
It means we're on our own.
我得去找媒體
I have to get in front of a camera.
可是長官 你一露面他們就會把你殺了
Well sir, they will kill you the second you show your face.
Bane說他要把哥譚還給市民
Bane says he's giving Gotham back to the people.
他們得知道我能引領他們
They need to know I could lead.
Bane不會讓這發生的
Bane is not going to let that happen.
- 那麼他就會露出本來面目 - 那你就死了
- Then he will show his true colors - Then you'd be dead.
在你們身後 正是壓迫的象徵
Behind you, stand a symbol of oppression.
黑門監獄 一千個人因為一個人被囚禁在這裡
Blackgate Prison, where a thousand men has languished under the name of this man
Harvey Dent
Harvey Dent.
他作為正義的閃亮標誌被呈現在你們面前
Who has been held to you as the shinning example of justice.
在你面對媒體之前我們的行動不能停下
We're just keep moving you until we can get you in front of a camera.
你們供奉著一個虛假的偶像
You have been supplied with a false idol,
為了讓你們不把這個墮落的城市撕成碎片
to stop you tearing down this corrupt city!
讓我告訴你Harvey Dent的真相吧
Let me tell you the truth about Harvey Dent!
這是哥譚警察局長的發言稿
From the prayers of Gotham Police Commissioner.
James Gordon
James Gordon.
蝙蝠俠沒有謀害Harvey Dent 他救了我的兒子
The Batman didn't murdered Harvey Dent, he saved my boy.
卻為Harvey Dent的駭人罪行背了黑鍋
Then took the blame for Harvey's appalling crimes,
我才可以毫無羞恥地
So that I could threw my shame,
為這個墮落的偶像編造謊言
build a lie around this fallen idol.
我歌頌一個試圖殺死我兒子的狂魔
I praised mad man who tried to kill my own child,
但我再也無法生活在謊言裡了
But I can no longer live with my lie.
是時候將真相公之於眾了
it's time to trust The people of Gotham with the truth
同時我也會引咎辭職
And it is time for me to resign.
那麼 你們接受這個人的辭呈嗎
And do you accept this man resignation?
你們接受所有這些腐敗者和騙子
And do you accept the resignations of all these liars,
的辭呈嗎
of all the corrupt?
那些人被關在黑門監獄長達八年
Those men locked up for 8 years at Blackgate with
僅僅因為一個建立在謊言上的法案而無法重獲自由
denied parole under the Dent's act based on a lie?
哥譚需要一個英雄
Gotham needed a hero.
比過去任何一個時期都更需要
It needs it now more than ever.
你背叛了自己的立場
You betrayed everything you stood for.
你以為我想嗎
What's the point?
那時的法制太無力
Far out there when the structures failing,
滿街的武器比手銬還多
and on the road, weapons city more than shackles
四處都是狂躁的犯罪分子
and letting the bad guy getting hit.
有一天你也可能面對這樣的危機
One day, you may face such a moment of crisis
在那時 我希望你像我一樣有個這樣的朋友
and in that moment I hope you have a friend like I did!
願意弄髒自己的聲名
To plunge their hands into the filth
保你清白
so that you can keep yours clean.
我看你的名聲已毀了 局長
Your hands looks pretty filthy to me, Commissioner.
我們從腐敗者手中奪回哥譚
We take Gotham from the corrupt.
從富人手中
The rich.
從那些借神之名世代壓迫
The oppressors who for generation
你們的人手中
has get you down with myth of opportunity,
我們把哥譚還給你們 人民們
and we give it back to you, the people.
哥譚是你們的 無人有權干涉
Gotham is yours. None shall interfered.
想做什麼就放手去做吧
Do as you pleased.
以轟開黑門監獄 解放受壓迫者為起點
and start by storming Blackgate and freeing the oppressed!
願為自由而戰的請上前
Step forward those who would serve.
新的世界將會崛起
To an army, a world will be raised.
將權貴從他們多年沉溺的迷夢中揪出
The powerful will be ripped from their decadent years...
然後丟棄在我們熟知並忍受的冰冷世界
and cast out into the cold world that we know and endure.
被人民的法庭傳喚審判
Courts will be convened.
財贓將由我們共享
Spoils will be enjoyed.
哥譚將被罪惡之血洗滌
Blood will be shed.
警察會倖存
The Police will survive
如果他們學會維護真正的正義
as they learn to serve true justice ...
這座偉大的城
This great city ...
將隱忍堅持
it will endure ...!
哥譚會倖存下來
Gotham will survive!
他說你要先治好你的背
He says you must first fix your back.
他怎麼知道
How does he know?
他是監獄的醫生 一個癮君子
He was the prison doctor. A morphine addict.
對嗎啡不能自拔
When heard of this pleasure of powerful evil,
你的面具朋友也是
including your mask friend.
怎麼
How?
很多年前 瘟疫氾濫的時候
Many years ago, it was a time of plague.
有些犯人傷了Bane
Some of the other prisoners attacked Bane.
醫生卻沒有盡力救他
The Doctor humbling attempt to rebuild the damage,
把Bane永遠留在了痛苦的深淵
left him in perpetual agony.
只能靠面具鎮住痛苦
The Mask hold the pain at bay.
貝恩就是那個逃出去的小孩 他生在這裡
Bane was the child who struck out? He was born here?
傳說曾有一個為當地軍閥效命的僱傭兵
Legend is that it was a mercenary who worked for a local warlord.
卻與軍閥的女兒墜入愛河
They felt in love with the warlord's daughter.
他們私定終身 最終被軍閥發現了
They were married in secret, but the warlord found out.
軍閥要把僱傭軍關到這個監獄
The mercenary was condemned to this pit.
但最終他只是被流放
But then he exiled him instead.
據我所知
The mess I understood that
是軍閥的女兒為他爭取到了自由
it was the daughter who secure his release.
但他並不知道 這自由的真正代價
But what he could not know, was the true price of his freedom.
是那個姑娘代替他坐牢
She took his place in the pit.
那時她已懷上了僱傭兵的孩子
And she was with child, the mercenary child.
無辜的花朵無法在地下盛開 等待它的必然是枯萎
Innocence cannot flower underground, it has to be stem out ...
有一天 醫生忘記鎖門
One day, the doctor forgot to lock the cell.
而那個孩子有一個朋友 一個守護者
But the child had a friend, a protector.
他試圖說服其他人這個孩子會是他們的救贖
Who showed the others that this innocence was their redemption.
但這是有代價的
It was to be priced.
而孩子的母親就沒有那麼幸運了
The mother was not so lucky.
這裡現在是Bane的監獄了 他不希望我們談論他
This is Bane's prison now. It wouldn't want this story told.
你背上有一塊脊椎突出來了
There's a vertebra protruding from your back.
要把它推回去
It has to be put back.
保持這個狀態直到你能站起來
Stay like this until you stand.
你沒想過我會回來嗎 Bruce
Did you not think I would return, Bruce?
我告訴過你我是不死之身
I told you I was immortal.
我親眼看著你死的
I watched you die!
哦 但是永生的形式有很多種
Oh they're many forms of immortality.
我曾經有一個妻子 我的至愛
Once I had a wife. My great love.
她被從我身邊奪走
She was taken from me.
你就是那個僱傭兵
You were the mercenary.
Bane是你的兒子 你的繼承人
Bane is your child, your heir.
我在這裡是確保影武者聯盟
I'm here to ensure The League of Shadow
完成其重建文明平衡的使命
fulfills it's duty to restore balance to civilization.
你為腐朽的哥譚市孤身奮鬥多年
You yourself fought the decadence of Gotham for years
用你的力量 你的資源
with all your strength, all your resources,
以及你的道德聲望
all your moral authority.
然而你唯一的成就卻是一個謊言
and the only victory you achieved was a lie.
現在 你明白了嗎 哥譚已無藥可救
Now, you understand? Gotham is beyond saving
它必須得死去
and must be allowed to die.
不
No!
-這是哪  -這曾是某人的家
- What's that? - This was someone's home.
現在是所有人的家了
Now, it's everyone's home.
風暴就要來了 記得嗎 正是我們期待的
There's storm coming remember? That is what we wanted.
這是給車上準備的 以防有撤離的機會
It's for the bus, in case there's a chance to evacuate.
-有局長的消息嗎 -你還是不知道的好 神父
- Any news from the Commissioner? - The less you know father..
孩子們現在怎麼樣
How are the boys doing?
恢復了一些電力 孩子們可以看電視了
Well we had more power on, so they get some TV.
-很高興看到你 神父 -Blake 你在外面小心一點
- It's good to see you father. - Blake, you be careful out there.
他們像惡犬一樣追殺警察
They hunting down cops like dogs.
-鍛煉有什麼意義呢 -我不該死在這裡
- Why build yourself? - I'm not meant to die in here.
這裡 那裡 又有什麼分別
Here or there, what's the difference?
我說過 不可能逃出升天的
I told you it can not be done.
你說過 有個孩子做到了
You told me a child did it.
可那不是一般的孩子 他生於地獄
But no ordinary child, a child born in hell,
長於苦難
forged from suffering,
痛苦讓他堅強
harden by pain.
不是你這樣的富家少爺
Not a man from privileged.
我們派人進去了
We got blues in the ground sir.
等消息吧
Just waiting on intel.
-有身份證明嗎 -當然沒有
- Do you have ID? - Of course not.
-那我們怎麼相信你 -我們別無選擇
- How can we trust you? - We don't have any choice.
Gorden局長 我是Jones上尉 特種部隊
Commissioner Gordon. Captain Jones, Special Forces.
-上尉 幸會 -職責所在
- Captain, glad to have you here. - It's our job sir.
現在你們有多少人
Now how many are all you are they?
幾十個吧 還是不說為好
Well there's dozen, I rather not say exactly.
但我們有近三千警察被困地下
The man trapped underground, numbered almost 3,000.
他們現在是什麼情況
What kind of condition are they in?
有水和食物
They been getting in food and water.
-我們能把他們救出來嗎 -可以 長官
- Can we break them out? - Yes, sir.
把守在Ackerman公園南部的
Take out the mercenaries
僱傭兵幹掉
guarding the outflows south of Ackerman Park,
炸開碎石 就能弄出一個一次夠十個人通行的洞
blow the rubble, we can make a hole big enough for 10 at a time.
我一直和我地下的搭檔保持著聯繫
I'm in contact with my partner down there.
他們等這一天等很久了
They're just waiting for the day.
指揮官 他們已經3個月沒有見過陽光了
Commander, they haven't seen daylight for three months.
他們是訓練有素的警察 這些對他們不是問題
Police officers who haven't seen daylight in three months.
那個核彈呢
What about the bomb?
衛星偵測不到任何紅外線熱點
The satellite can't pick up any radiation hot spots.
他們把核彈放在卡車上 一定是鉛頂的
They keep it on a truck. It must have lead lined roof.
-卡車不曾停過 -很好 那你知道是哪輛車嗎
- They're moving constantly. - Good, so you know the truck?
肯定是三輛中的一輛 我們已經在追蹤它們了
Well it's one of the three. We've been tracking it.
這個不是
Decoy.
你不會真的相信他會回來 是吧
You're not really think he's coming back, do you?
我怎麼想的並不重要
Doesn't matter what I think.
事實上很重要
Actually it does.
你應該把你的信念建立在更實際的事物之上
You should put your faith in something more real.
路線沒有更改過
But the routes don't vary much.
-那個引爆者呢 -沒有線索 應該是假的
- What about the trigger man? - No leads. It's a bluff.
Bane不會把引爆器的控制權假手於人的
Bane wouldn't gave control on that to someone else.
我們不能冒這個險
We can't take that chance.
在找到引爆者前 得繼續追蹤卡車
Until we have the trigger man, we just track the device.
同時就讓哥譚處於軍閥管控下嗎
And mean while, Gotham lives under a warlord?
就像某些淪陷的國家
Like some failed state?
意見駁回 警官 這形勢是前所未見的
Dialed it back, officer. The situation is unprecedented.
我們不能拿數百萬的生命來冒險
We can't do anything to risk million of lives.
你不打算說明嗎
Can't you tell? Aren't you
你不打算告訴他們到底發生了什麼嗎
going to tell them what actually is going on?
情況要遠比你想像的複雜 上尉
Captain, the situation is more complicated than you think.
有個人 你得見一見
There's someone you need to meet.
我曾上樓尋找戰鬥制高點
Came up stairs looking for a vantage point.
發現公司的高層住在這上面
Found the people who runs the corporation living up here.
什麼公司
What corporation?
韋恩集團
Wayne Enterprises.
Fox先生 你能向上尉簡單介紹一下嗎
Mr. Fox would you like to brief the captain?
Tate小姐 對情況非常瞭解
Mrs. Tate is fully aware of the situation.
作為韋恩集團的首席執行官
As the CEO of Wayne Enterprises,
我必須對此負責
I have to take responsibility for it.
-為什麼 -因為我們創造了它
- Why? - We built it.
你們做了這個核彈
You built the bomb?
最初是以供能反應堆來建造的 是好事
It was build as a fussion reactor. First of it's kind
Bane把它變成了核彈 並帶出了反應堆
Bane turned the core into a bomb, and remove it from the reactor.
這是最重要的部分
That's the important part.
隨著設備的能源單元衰變
As the device's fuel cells deteriorates,
它逐漸變得不穩定 最終爆炸
it becomes increasingly unstable to the point of detonation.
-這是個定時核彈 -而且23天後就會爆炸
- This bomb is a time bomb. - And it will go off in 23 days.
不管Bane的革命如何進行
Regardless of the Bane's revolution or what we
不管我們和外界如何行動
and the outside world choose to do.
你的不冒險計劃不像你想得那麼可操作
Your peace-man plan may not be as practical as you thought.
你能拆除它嗎
Could you disarm it?
我可以把它重新插入反應堆使之穩定
I could reconnect to the reactor to stabilize it.
我們撤 行動吧
Let's move away from this location and call it in.
好 我們走
Alright let's go!
現在我來負責 你們留下照顧他們
Let me take it from here. You stay and look after these folks.
有人出賣了我們
Someone sold us out.
我死也不說
I'd die before I talk.
那你就去死吧 上尉
How about new schedule, Captain.
樓上有人居住
There were people living upstairs.
把他們抓起來送去審判
Round them up for judgment.
然後把他們的屍體懸掛展示給世人
And hang them where the world to see.
他說 那逃脫的一躍靠的不是身體力量
He says that the leap of freedom is not about strength.
-但是我要用我的身體來完成跳躍 -是想要倖存的信念
- My body makes the jump. - Surviving is spirit
是靈魂
the soul
我的靈魂已經準備好了和身體一起逃離
My soul, it is ready to escape with my body
你恐懼的是恐懼本身嗎
Fear is what you afraid?
不 我不恐懼
No, I'm not afraid.
我憤怒
I'm angry.
Bruce
Bruce ...
我們為什麼會墜落
Why did we fall?
你不恐懼死亡
You do not fear death.
你認為這使你強大  其實它使你變的軟弱
You think this makes you strong? It makes you weak.
為什麼
Why?
一個人如何能有超常人的行動力
How can you move faster than possible?
超常人的戰鬥力
Fight longer than possible?
而心中卻沒有最強大的驅動力
Without the most powerful impulse left in you.
對死亡的恐懼
The fear of death.
我恐懼死亡
I fear death.
我恐懼我就在這裡死去 而我的城市卻在水深火熱
I fear dying in here, all my city burns,
沒人可以拯救
there's no one there to save it.
那就從這裡爬出去
And then make the climb!
怎麼爬
How?
就像那個孩子一樣
As the child did.
不用繩子
Without the rope.
直面你的恐懼
That fear will fight you again.
啊 你竟然還沒放棄 很好啊
Ah surprise for your journey, that's wonderful.
- 他們在喊什麼 - 崛起
- What does that mean? - Rise.
不需要
No.
你們搞錯了 帶我去見Bane
There's been a mistake. Take me to Bane!
Bane在哪兒
Where's Bane?
沒搞錯 Stryver先生 Philip Stryver
There's no mistake Mr. Stryver. You are Philip Stryver.
Daggett公司的執行副總裁
Executive Vice President of Daggett Industries?
多年來壓搾弱者血汗
Who for years has been living off the blood
供自己享樂的傢伙
and sweat of people less powerful than him!
叫Bane來 我是自己人
Call Bane! I am one of you.
Bane不管這事兒 這不過是個量刑聽證會
Bane has no authority here. This is merely a sentencing hearing.
你選吧 流放還是死刑
Now chooses are yours: exile or death?
- 流放 - 成交
- Exile. - Sold!
先生別太緊張嘛
The man of the cold sweat.
沿著厚冰走
You follow the thick ice.
想遊走的 即刻槍決
If you try to swim, you're dead in minutes.
沒人活下來麼
So no one made it?
他們都死到哪兒去了
Where the hell are they?
我們時間緊迫
It's not like we have a lot of time here.
- 還有多久 - 核彈明天就要爆了
- How long? - The bomb goes off tomorrow.
我們還有18個小時補救
We have about 18 hours to do something.
怎麼補救
To do what?
給卡車作標記 裝個GPS上去
To mark the truck. Get a GPS on it,
然後我們才能想辦法逐個擊破
so we can start to figure out how to bring it down.
就這些?
That's it?
Foley
Foley!
Foley哪兒去了 他媽的
Where is Foley? Damn it!
你不能上街的
You shouldn't be out in the streets.
Jim 他不在家
Jim, he's not here.
城市陷入魔掌
You let your wife come to the door,
你卻躲在妻子身後
when the city is under occupation?
你怎麼了 把制服埋在後院了麼
What did you do? Bury your uniform in the backyard?
你也看到他們把特警部隊怎麼了
You saw what they did to the special forces.
你忘了我們當差巡邏的日子了嗎
Have you forgotten all the years we were out on patrolled?
當年那些匪徒們
When every gang banger want
我們稍一調頭就想給我們吃槍子
to plant one as soon as our back are turned?
今時不同往日你比誰都清楚 哥譚市任人魚肉
Now is different and you know it. This guys run the city.
政府和他們訂了協議
The government is done a deal with them.
是Bane威逼他們 那不算協議
Bane's got their balls on the ice that's not a deal.
如果你對Bane下手 那個引爆者就會引爆核彈的
If you move on Bane, the trigger-man is going to hit the button.
你真以為他會把核彈引爆器
Do you think he's given
交給某一個市民嗎
control of that bomb to one of the people?
你覺得他們在鬧革命嗎
You think this apart of some revolutions?
引爆器只由一人掌控 那就是Bane
There's only one man with his finger on the button, that's Bane.
聽著 在恐慌結束前 還是不要輕舉妄動的好
Look we all got to keep our heads down until they can fix this.
如果你也有家庭
If you had family here ...
哥譚只能靠我們自己拯救
It's only get fix from inside the city.
聽著 Peter 我不是要你
Look Peter, I'm not asking you
穿著制服上街抓賊
to walk down grand in you dress rules,
但有些事必須做
but something has to be done.
- 對不起 Jim 我不能 - 你給我清醒點
- I'm sorry, Jim. I gotta... - Keep your head down..
那玩意兒明天就爆了 你又能怎樣呢
What's good that going to do tomorrow when that thing blows.
又不是你說了算
You don't know that's going to happens.
聽說你缺人手 警長
I hear you're looking for men Commissioner?
我行麼
How about me instead?
- Tate小姐 這太危險了 - 拜託了
- Miss Tate, I can't ask you to do that. - Please.
- 你偷什麼了 - 沒什麼
- What you did? - Nothing.
我什麼都沒偷
I didn't take anything.
敢偷我們的東西 你這小兔崽子
You steal from us? You little bastard.
現在你們知道
Now you boys know you can't come in my
別在我的地盤撒野了吧
neighborhood without asking politely.
不要從能追上你的人手裡偷東西 孩子
Never steal anything from someone you can't outrun, kid!
你個小賊 還挺大方的
You're pretty generous for a thief!
- 還以為你死了呢 - 還沒呢
- I thought they killed you. - Not yet.
- 如果你在等我道歉的話 - 我知道你不會
- If you expecting an apology ... - It wouldn't suit you.
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.
- 為什麼我要幫你 - 為了 "清洗程序"
- And why would I help you? - For this. ' Clean Slate '.
我把你害成那樣 你還信我
You trust me with that, after what I did to you?
我得承認我有些失望
I admit I was a little let down.
但我依然相信你心裡更好的一面
But I still think there more to you.
事實上 我認為 對你來說 這不只是個工具
In fact that, I think that. For you, this isn't just a tool.
你想借此消失 重新開始
It's an escape route you want to disappear, start fresh.
我連這個島都出不了
I couldn't even get off this island.
帶我去找Lucius Fox 我能幫你找到一條路
I could give you a way off once you to get me to Lucius Fox.
我要你查出他關在哪兒 帶我去
I need you to find out where they're holding him and take me in.
- 為什麼找Fox - 為了拯救這座城
- Why do you need Fox? - To save the city.
誰說哥譚需要被拯救 我挺喜歡這樣的
Who says it needs saving? Maybe I like it this way.
你喜歡而已
Maybe you do.
但核彈明天就要爆了
But tomorrow that bomb is going off.
你神勇的朋友回歸了麼
Get your powerful friend on the case?
我會盡力的 但我需要Fox
I'm trying, but I need Fox.
等車靠近了 按下開關
Once it approaches, flick the switch.
針跳到了200 就給我個信號
The needle hit 200, you give me the signal.
我就給車作標記 好嗎
I'll will mark truck. Okay?
車來了 車來了
Heads up! Heads up!
- 有指數了 - 六點鐘方向有僱傭兵
- I got it! - Mercenaries at your 6.
別動 手舉在我們能看到的地方
Stand still! Keep your hands where we can see them!
Gordon局長 你被捕了
Commissioner Gordon, you're under arrest.
誰給你的權利
On who's authority?
哥譚人民
People of Gotham.
沒律師 沒證人 這算什麼聽證會
No lawyer. No witnesses. What sort of due process is this?
你已經被認定有罪了
You guilt have been determined.
這不過是量刑聽證會
This is merely a sentencing hearing.
你選什麼
Now what will it be?
死刑還是流放
Death or exile?
Crane 你以為我們會自願走上冰層麼
Crane, if you think we're going out on that ice willingly,
你錯了
you have another thing coming.
- 那就是死刑咯 - 我想是的
- Death then. - Looks that way.
很好 死刑
Very well. Death!
以流放的形式
By exile.
帶她來見我
Bring her to me!
嘿 下來 準備好
Hey. Going down. Get things ready.
行動開始
Let's gear on.
抓到了這傢伙 明天有得忙了
Spot this one on the spot. Got a big day tomorrow.
就是啊 不是每天都能逮到Bruce Wayne的
We all do. Not every day you bag Bruce Wayne!
- Bruce - 你沒事吧
- Bruce? - You okay?
你太會挑時間旅行了 Wayne先生
You pick the hell of time to go on vacation, Mr. Wayne.
我們還有多少時間
How long until that core ignites?
那核彈還有12個小時就炸了
That bomb goes off in 12 hours.
除非我們把它弄回反應堆裡
Unless we can reconnect it to the reactor.
- 你能把Miranda帶出去嗎 - 今晚不行 抱歉了
- Can you get Miranda out of here? - Not tonight. I'm sorry.
- 做你要做的 - 今晚我需要你
- Do what necessary. - Tonight I need you.
- 做什麼 - 讓我重回戰場
- What for? - To get me back in the game.
不好意思 掃你們的興了
Sorry to spoil things
孩子們 他們想親自處理這幾個人
boys but they want these guys to themselves.
- 我不會忘記我們事的 Miranda - 我知道
- I won't forget about us, Miranda! - I know.
- 我喜歡你的女朋友 Wayne先生 - 女朋友個頭
- I like your girlfriend, Mr. Wayne! - He should be so lucky.
我動一下Bane或是那炸彈
Any move I make on Bane or the bomb,
觸發者都會引爆炸彈
the trigger-man will set it off.
他們不會用無線電或是手機信號 太多干擾了
They won』t use radio or cell, too much interference.
紅外線的範圍沒那麼廣
Infrared doesn't have the range.
一定是某種長射程的微型脈衝
It had to be a Micro-burst, long-range.
- 你能攔截嗎 - 能
- Can you block it? - Yes.
但我需要蝙蝠車上的頻率捕獲器
But I need the EMP cannon guidance mounted on the Bat.
記得你停在哪兒了嘛
Remember where you parked it?
- 飛起來還好吧 - 好啊
- It fly okay? - Yeah.
雖然不能自動駕駛 真是謝謝了
Even without the autopilot. Thanks.
自動駕駛 你自己不能開啊
Autopilot? That's what you're there for.
安全了 來吧 快 過來
Thing's clear. Come on, quick! Climb.
封鎖起來
Lock it up!
你是誰
Who are you?
點燃它
Light it up!
媽媽 你看
Mom check it out.
親愛的 快看
Honey, take a look!
不可思議
Impossible!
看緊她 他會回來救她的
Keep her close! He'll come for her.
- Miranda Tate在哪兒 - Bane帶走了她
- Where's Miranda Tate? - Bane took her.
他佔領了市議會 守衛森嚴
He holds up city hall, surrounded by his army.
這個會截斷引爆信號
This blocks detonator signal to the bomb.
在日出前裝好
Get it on to it before sunrise.
必要的話 我會在開始時引爆核彈的
If I hit the button when it starts.
- 什麼開始時 - 戰爭
- When what start? - War.
還有一個沒倒呢
You missed a spot.
如果你獨自一人行俠仗義 戴個面具
If you're working alone, wear a mask!
我不畏懼直面他們
I'm not afraid if they see me standing up to these guys.
面具不為保護自己
The mask is not for you,
是為了保護你在意的人
it's to protect the people you care about.
數到五丟出去
Count to five and throw.
嘿 無意冒犯 但你就沒有火力大點的東西嗎
Hey no offense, but you got something bigger in that belt?
- 現在怎麼辦 - 全力攻擊Bane
- What now? - All out assault on Bane.
但你得帶人們過橋
But you need to get people across the bridge.
為什麼
Why?
以免我們失敗了 離開哥譚 能救多少救多少
In case we fail. Leave an exodus. Save as many lives as you can.
- 你不需要我嗎 - 你已經給了我一支軍隊 現在 快走
- You don't need me here? - You given me an army. Now, go!
- 好吧 謝謝 - 先別謝我
- Alright, thanks! - Don't thank me yet.
我怕以後就沒機會了
Well I might not get the chance later.
你真是太客氣了
You shouldn't have.
隧道被殘骸堵住了
All in town tunnel blocked by debris.
但加農炮的火力足夠為人們開道
But the cannon have anough fire power to make a path for people.
等到戰鬥開始前
Wait until the fighting begins!
你要為了你女友升級這場戰爭嗎
You going to wage your war to save your stuck up girlfriend?
要發動 閥門
To start it, throttle.
我會開
I got it.
你有45分鐘拯救哥譚
We have 45 minutes to save the city.
不 我有45分鐘逃離炸彈輻射區
No. I got 45 minutes to get clear of the blast radius.
因為你毫無勝算
because you don't stand a chance against these guys.
有你幫助 也許還有希望
With your help, I might.
我會打開隧道 然後離開
I open that tunnel, but then I'm gone.
你心裡有更好的一面
There's more to you than that.
不好意思一直讓你失望
Sorry to keep letting you down.
跟我走吧 救救你自己
Come with me! Save yourself!
你不欠那些人什麼 你已經為他們付出了一切
You don't owe these people anymore. You given them everything.
不是一切 還沒有
Not everything. Not yet.
散開 散開不然格殺勿論
Disperse! Disperse or be fired upon!
這座城裡只有一個警察局
There's only one police in this town,
開火
Open fire!
- 來了 - 準備好
- Here it comes. - Get ready!
所以你回來給你的城市陪葬麼
So you came back to die with your city!
不 我回來阻止你
No. I came back to stop you.
現在
Now!
這不可能
That's impossible.
去第五大道!
Come over the fifth!
上車 去 你過來 你也是
Get on the bus, go ahead. You come with me! You too!
嘿 你 你和你 過來
Hey you, you and you, come here!
其他人上車 好麼
Everyone else get on the bus! Okay.
你們 挨家挨戶的敲門
You guys, you're going
把消息傳開 就說
to knock on doors and spread the word okay.
炸彈快爆炸了 從南街隧道離開
The bomb going to go off. Get out by South Street tunnel.
或者穿過橋
or over the bridge.
每個人兩個街區
You go, you do two blocks,
傳完話就回車上來 好嗎 去吧
you get back to the bus. Alright? Go! Go!
- 他回來了嗎 - 等著看吧 快走
- Is he back? - Keep your eyes open. Go!
去守門
Cover the doors!
引爆器在哪兒 在哪兒
Where's your trigger? Where is it?
你不會給普通市民的
You never gave it to any ordinary citizen.
在哪兒 引爆器在哪兒
Where is it? Where's the trigger?
在哪兒
Where is it?
告訴我引爆器在哪兒
Tell me where the trigger is.
然後 我准許你死
Then, you have my permission to die.
我把你廢了 你怎麼回來的
I broke you. How did you come back?
你以為你是唯一一個
You think you're the only
可以從那逃離的人嗎
one who could learn the strength to escape?
- 引爆器在哪兒 - 但我從未逃離過
- Where's the trigger? - But I never escaped.
但那孩子
But the child,
忍者大師的孩子 飛躍淵井的孩子
Child of Ra's Al Ghul's, who made the climb.
但他不是忍者大師的孩子
But he's not the child of Ra's Al Ghul.
我才是
I am.
儘管我並不普通 但我也是個市民
Although I'm not ordinary, I'm a citizen.
Miranda
Miranda?
為什麼
Why?
Talia 我媽媽臨死前 給我取名叫Talia
Talia. My mother named me Talia before she was killed.
如果不是Bane一直守護我 我也早就死了
The way I have been killed if not for my protector, Bane.
再見
Good bye.
我爬出了淵井
I climbed out of the pit.
找到了我的父親
I found my father
帶他回去血債血償
and brought him back to exact terrible vengeance.
但那時
But by that time,
獄徒們和醫生已經對我的朋友下了毒手
the prisoners and the doctor had their work to my friend,
我的守護者
my protector.
影武者聯盟接納了我們 訓練了我們
The League took us in and trained us
但我的父親無法接受Bane
but my father could not accept Bane.
他認為他是魔鬼 他的存在
He saw only a monster, whose very existence
象徵著他妻子被囚禁並死去的地獄
was the reminder of the hell he left his wife to die in.
他把Bane逐出了影武者聯盟
He excommunicated Bane from The League of Shadows.
他唯一的罪就是他愛上了我
His only crime was that he loved me.
我一直無法原諒我的父親
I could not forgive my father.
直到你殺了他
Until you murdered him.
他試圖殺死數以百萬的無辜之人
He was trying to kill millions of innocent people.
在哥譚 無辜這個詞未免言過其實
Innocence is a strong word to throw around Gotham roose.
我以完成他的大業向他致敬
I honor my father by finishing his work.
手刃殺父仇人
Vengeance against the man who killed
不過是對我耐心的獎勵
him is simply a reward for my patience.
你看
You see?
就是這種遲鈍的刀子 這種花時間的刀子
It's the slow knife. The knife that takes it's time.
那種隱忍多年 充滿執念的刀子
The knife that wait years, without forgetting,
悄然滑入骨間
then slip quietly between the bones,
入肉最深
that's the knife that cut deepest.
求求你
Please!
也許那刀子太鈍了
Maybe that knife was too slow.
卡車被襲擊了
The truck is under attacked.
Gordon 你給了他屏蔽我的信號的方法
Gordon. You gave him a way to block my signal
無所謂
No matter.
哥譚不過能多苟延殘喘11分鐘而已
He's bought Gotham 11 minutes.
快點
Come on!
退回去 你想幹嘛
Stay back! What are you doing?
Blake 重案組 我要送他們去安全的地方
Blake. MCU, I'm getting these boys to safety
你會害死我們的
You're going to get us all killed.
如果有人越過這座橋 他們就會炸了整座城
If anyone cross this bridge, they'll blow up the city.
反正都會爆炸的 我們需要打開這座橋 現在
It going to blow up anyway. We need to open this bridge, now!
警官 如果你向前一步 我們就開槍了
Detective, if you take one step forward we will shoot you!
如果再走一步 我們就會炸橋
If you do two forward, we will blow the bridge.
回車上等我
Go back to the bus and wait for me alright!
回去等著就好
Just go back and wait.
他們準備了護送隊
They've prepared a convoy.
我們必須在炸彈爆炸之前保護好它
We must secure the bomb until it detonates!
別殺了他 我想讓他感受那熱浪
Don't kill him. I want him to feel the heat.
1200萬個靈魂 燃燒的熱浪
Heat the fire of 12 million souls.
你失敗了
You failed!
再見了 我的朋友
Good bye, my friend!
繼續向前 奪回那階梯
Keep moving forward! Take back the stairs!
殺了他們
Shoot them!
殺無赦
Shoot them all!
我們都知道 我現在就得殺了你
We both know that I have to kill you now.
你只能想像那股熱浪了
You have just to imagine the fire.
你的不殺人政策
About the whole no guns thing,
真是很難認同
I'm not sure I feel strongly about it as you do.
趕上去
Pull up!
保持速度
Stay level.
我們得把他們逼回反應堆的入口
We have to force them to the entrance of the reactor.
我要你在地面支援 我先離開 走
I need you on the ground. I'll be leaving. Go!
形勢改變了 你的指令已過時
The situation has changed! Your orders are out of date.
我和你一樣是警察 現在我就要走過去了
I'm a cop like you and I'm walking out there.
請不要開槍
Please do not shoot me!
射他的膝蓋
Shoot at his knee.
空中優勢很不錯吧
Nothing like a little air superiority.
警官 請停下 求你了 警官 快停下
Detective, please stop! Please, detective! Stop!
快停下 炸掉橋 炸啊
Stop walking! Blow it! Do it!
快把核彈帶回來 你只有10分鐘
They have to get that bomb here and you got ten minutes.
他們想把我們逼回反應堆入口
They're pushing us to the entrance of the reactor!
他們想把核彈放回去
They're going to try to reconnect the core.
蠢貨
Idiots!
你個混蛋 是你害死了他們
You son-of-bitches! You killed them.
你就知道按章行事
You're just following orders!
好了 孩子們站好 低下頭
Alright boys get in circle, bow your heads.
沒多少時間了
Not much longer.
都回車上 好嗎
Let's get everyone back in the bus. Okay?
走走 回車上
Go! Go! Back in the bus.
回車上又能去哪裡
There's no where to go!
回車上
On the bus!
必須把卡車逼向左轉
You got to turn the truck EAST!
直走
Stay straight!
幫我  把它放回反應堆
Give me a hand! We can get a cable on it!
Fox告訴過我怎麼重置反應堆
Fox showed me how overwrite reactor.
我的天
Oh dear.
包括緊急灌水
Including the emergency flood.
這炸彈絕不可能停下來
There's no way this bomb will be stopped.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
從輻射裡保護他們
Protect them from the blast!
我們會沒事的 快點兒 快
We're going to be alright! Double time! Go!
那是原子彈
It's an atom bomb!
你覺得他們應該知道這些嗎
You think they need to hear that right now?
你想讓他們充滿絕望的死去麼 快啊
You want to watch them die without hope? Come on!
準備去死吧
Prepare yourself.
我父親的大業就要完成了
My father's work is done.
- 你在做什麼 - 我能把它弄出海灣去
- What are you doing? - I can get it out over the bay.
- 無人駕駛到海裡麼- 我來駕駛
- Set it to fly over water and eject? - No autopilot.
你本可以在任何地方 做任何事 但你回來了
You could've gone anywhere, did anything but you came back here.
- 你也是 - 我想我們腦子都壞了
- So did you. - I guess we're both suckers.
- 我從不在乎你是誰 - 這才對
- I never cared who you were. - And you were right.
但人們不該知道救他們的英雄是誰嗎
Shouldn't the people know the hero who saved them?
英雄可以是任何人
Hero can be anyone.
甚至他不過是
Even a man knowing something as simple as
給一個小男孩披上衣服
reassuring putting a coat around a young boy
告訴他生活並沒有結束
shoulders to let him the world hadn't end then.
Bruce Wayne
Bruce Wayne?
Vlad 快點 你們也是 到車裡去
Vlad, they go! You too! Come on father.
嘿 低頭 爆炸了
Hey heads down! This is it!
不 是蝙蝠俠
No! That's Batman!
爆炸了
That's detonation!
遠離海灣 哥譚沒事了
It's out over the bay, it's clear of the city.
"我看到 一座美麗的城" (以下出自狄更斯小說)
' I see a beautiful city '
"和那些從廢墟中崛起的人們"
' and the the brilliant people rising from this abyss. '
"我看到 為他人獻出生命的使者"
' I see the lives, for which I lay down my life.'
"和平的 可用的 繁盛的 快樂的"
' Peaceful, useful, prosperous and happy. '
"我看到 我在他們和他們後代心中"
' I see that I hold a sanctuary in their hearts '
"留下了神聖的印記"
' And in the hearts of their decedents. '
"時代的終結"
' Generations ends. '
"那是遠遠好過了"
' That's the far, far better thing that I do... '
"我所做過的 一切事情"
'... than I had ever done. '
"因此我的長眠遠遠好過了"
' and It's a far, far better rest that I go to...'
"我所知的一切"
' ... than I had ever known. '
對不起 我讓你們失望了
I'm so sorry. I failed you!
你們如此信任我
You trusted me ...
而我卻讓你們失望了
And I failed you.
我還能改變你的主意麼
Can't I change your mind,
辭職這件事
about quitting the force?
你記得你說過的關於規則變成束縛
You know you said about structures becoming shackles.
你說的對 而我無法忍受 這是不公的
You were right and I can't take it, it's injustice.
我的意思是
I mean
沒人會知道是誰救了這座城市
No one ever going to know who saved the entire city.
他們知道
They know.
蝙蝠俠
It was The Batman.
Wayne先生的遺言 規定他的住所
Mr. Wayne's will is not amended to reflect his more modest estate.
以及 他的多處房產和宅子裡的東西將被出售
Nonetheless, they're considerable assets to dispose of.
獲利所得將作為慈善基金使用
The content of the house are to be sold to settle the state accounts.
而那些剩餘的歸屬於Alfred J. Pennyworth
and the remainders left in it's entirety to Alfred J. Pennyworth.
宅子和所有房產有條件的奉獻給哥譚市
The house and grounds are left to the city of Gotham on condition
它們不得被毀壞以及各種形式的整改 要永遠保持現在的樣子
that they never be demolish, altered or otherwise interfered with.
它們只能被用於孤兒福利
That they shall be used for one purpose and one purpose only:
或是緊急避難所
The housing and care of the city's at risk and orphan children.
僅我微小
And I clerk and help anyone with
以達眾生
a small correspondences and instruction.
- Blake John - 沒東西在這兒
- Blake, John? - Nothing here.
好吧
Alright,
試試我的本名
Try my legal name.
你應該用你的全名 很好聽 Robin
You should use your full name. I like that name, Robin.
謝謝
Thanks!
你何必擔心穩定化的軟件系統
Why are we even worrying about stabilization software?
這個自動駕駛系統實在太過時了
This entire autopilot system is completely obsolete.
拜託 我只是想知道我怎麼才能修好它
Please, I just need to know what I could've done to fix it.
但Fox先生 它已經修好了
But Mr. Fox it's already been fixed,
軟件修正 6個月前
software patch, six months ago.
查查修正的ID
Check The ID on the patch.
Bruce Wayne
Bruce Wayne.
- 有遺失物的消息嗎 - 還沒
- Any news on the missing item? - Not yet.
最好把失物都找回
Better leave no stone unturned.
那珍珠項鏈不能就這麼被偷走
We can't leave a string of pearl on the manifest flaws.
噢 在晨曦初現時 你可看見*  (美國國歌)
Oh, say can you see by the dawn's early light
是什麼讓我們如此驕傲*
What so proudly we hailed at the twilight's last gleaming?
在黎明的最後一道曙光中歡呼*
Whose broad stripes and bright stars thru the perilous fight
是誰的旗幟在激戰中始終高揚*
O'er the ramparts we watched were so gallantly streaming?
烈火熊熊 炮聲隆隆*
And the rocket's red glare, the bombs bursting in air
我們看到要塞上那面英勇的旗幟在黑暗過後依然聳立*
Gave proof thru the night that our flag was still there
啊 你說那星條旗是否會靜止*
Oh, say does that star-spangled banner yet wave
在自由的土地上飄舞 在勇者的家園上飛揚*
O'er the land of the free and the home of the brave
電波字幕組
誠意製作
翻譯：泥巴 陶仔 PADA L君 三好 憤豆
校對：泥巴 憤豆 英俊君
時間軸：英俊君
總監：英俊君